We composers are a pretty bruised bunch.
It’s bad enough that we don’t even have a good name
...for the type of music that we write.
The best we can think of is the oxymoron:
'Contemporary
'Contemporary classical'
But on top of that,
...our choice of notation software has generally been
...substandard and expensive.
And where other creative professions
...have industry standards, such as:
Photoshop
Maya
Premiere
After Effects
Pro Tools
...et cetera,
...our industry standards are still:
Sibelius
...and Finale.
And after I released my video
about the design of Sibelius,
...I realised that I’d tapped into an almost
...unanimous frustration with the existing offerings,
...a shared pain
...felt across the world of modern composition.
And I’ve been contacted multiple times by people
...who’ve said that they prefer to write scores by hand,
...because the existing offerings
...are just too slow and frustrating.
Wow.
I don’t know if I’ve ever heard an author
...say they prefer the efficiency of a pen.
But the good news is that
...the field has opened up over the last few years,
...and with more competition,
...comes cross-pollination, and hopefully,
...the incentive for everyone to do better,
...you'd hope.
But which application should we look at next?
Well.
To figure that out,
...I decided to put it to a YouTube poll.
And man,
...was my expectation way off.
MuseScore,
...by a country mile.
Really?
MuseScore?
Well, it has a pretty strong following,
...especially among younger audiences,
...with over 60% of its users
...coming in under the age of 24.
Them some good demographics.
And its feature set isn’t quite as lightweight
...as its cost implies either.
It’s also accompanied by an impressive
...online score-sharing application.
And just looking through it,
...you can get the sense of a pretty thriving community.
People can upload their scores,
...receive ratings,
...and as you’re listening to other people’s work,
...you can make comments like:
W-
What!?
Um...
U
Uu
Uuu
Uuuu
Uuuuu
Uuuuur
Uuuuurr
Uuuuurrr
Uuuuurrrg
Uuuuurrrgh
Uuuuurrrghh
Anyway,
...despite this impressive combination of offerings,
...it ain't perfect.
And when looking at its design,
...three things immediately jumped out at me.
And these will be the design focus for this video:
The practical value of visual style,
...the importance of getting the navigation right early,
...and most importantly for a notation app:
How the tiny details
...really, really matter.
Now,
...through the course of this video,
...I’m going to be saying some:
...and I’m going to say some:
But most importantly,
...I’m going to be saying some:
S- Sorry.
F- Fair things!
I- Look- [chuckles]
I’m going to be fair.
So,
...MuseScore is the brainchild of:
...a German developer and music enthusiast,
...who, up until 2002,
...had been working on an open source sequencing app
...called ‘MusE’,
...which looked like this.
And if we look up here,
...we can see what I’m guessing is
...the Lyre of the muse:
Cute.
My muse is Shostakovich.
Look!
Here he is sitting beside my desk.
Anyway,
...one day,
...as Werner was working,
...the Lyre began to glow.
And as he looked on,
...Terpsichore appeared before him
...and speaketh thus:
“𝖂𝖊𝖗𝖓𝖊𝖗..."
"...𝖉𝖔 𝖞𝖔𝖚 𝖓𝖔𝖙 𝖙𝖍𝖎𝖓𝖐 𝖙𝖍𝖆𝖙 𝖙𝖍𝖊𝖗𝖊 𝖆𝖑𝖗𝖊𝖆𝖉𝖞 𝖊𝖝𝖎𝖘𝖙𝖘"
"...𝖆𝖓 𝖔𝖛𝖊𝖗-𝖆𝖇𝖚𝖓𝖉𝖆𝖓𝖈𝖊 𝖔𝖋 𝖆𝖚𝖉𝖎𝖔-𝖕𝖗𝖔𝖉𝖚𝖈𝖙𝖎𝖔𝖓 𝖆𝖕𝖕𝖘?"
"𝕴𝖘 𝖎𝖙 𝖓𝖔𝖙 𝖎𝖓 𝖋𝖆𝖈𝖙 𝖙𝖍𝖊 𝖈𝖆𝖘𝖊"
"...𝖙𝖍𝖆𝖙 𝖜𝖍𝖆𝖙 𝖙𝖍𝖎𝖘 𝖗𝖊𝖆𝖑𝖒 𝖙𝖗𝖚𝖑𝖞 𝖈𝖗𝖆𝖛𝖊𝖘"
"...𝖎𝖘 𝖆 𝖉𝖎𝖌𝖎𝖙𝖆𝖑 𝖓𝖔𝖙𝖆𝖙𝖎𝖔𝖓 𝖆𝖕𝖕"
"...𝖋𝖗𝖊𝖊 𝖔𝖋 𝖓𝖔𝖓𝖘𝖊𝖓𝖘𝖊?"
"𝕱𝖔𝖗 𝕾𝖎𝖇𝖊𝖑𝖎𝖚𝖘 𝖆𝖓𝖉 𝕱𝖎𝖓𝖆𝖑𝖊,"
"...𝖔𝖓𝖈𝖊 𝖛𝖎𝖗𝖙𝖚𝖔𝖚𝖘,"
"...𝖍𝖆𝖛𝖊 𝖔𝖋 𝖑𝖆𝖙𝖊"
"...𝖋𝖆𝖑𝖑𝖊𝖓 𝖚𝖓𝖉𝖊𝖗 𝖙𝖍𝖊 𝖒𝖆𝖑𝖎𝖌𝖓 𝖎𝖓𝖋𝖑𝖚𝖊𝖓𝖈𝖊 𝖔𝖋:"
"...𝖆𝖓𝖉:"
"𝕬𝖓𝖉 𝖙𝖍𝖔𝖘𝖊 𝖜𝖍𝖔 𝖘𝖙𝖚𝖉𝖞 𝖙𝖍𝖊 𝖆𝖓𝖈𝖎𝖊𝖓𝖙 𝖆𝖗𝖙𝖘"
"...𝖆𝖗𝖊 𝖎𝖓 𝖌𝖗𝖊𝖆𝖙 𝖕𝖆𝖎𝖓."
Werner agreed
...that this was in fact the case,
...and asked what he could do to help.
“𝕮𝖗𝖊𝖆𝖙𝖊 𝖆𝖓 𝖆𝖑𝖙𝖊𝖗𝖓𝖆𝖙𝖎𝖛𝖊 𝖋𝖔𝖗 𝖒𝖊,"
"...𝖉𝖊𝖘𝖈𝖊𝖓𝖉𝖆𝖓𝖙 𝖔𝖋 𝕻𝖆𝖓,"
"...𝖆𝖓𝖉 𝖒𝖆𝖐𝖊 𝖎𝖙 𝖋𝖗𝖊𝖊."
"𝕱𝖗𝖊𝖊 𝖋𝖔𝖗 𝖙𝖍𝖊 𝖕𝖊𝖔𝖕𝖑𝖊!"
"𝕯𝖔 𝖙𝖍𝖎𝖘,"
"...𝖆𝖓𝖉 𝕴 𝖘𝖍𝖆𝖑𝖑 𝖘𝖍𝖔𝖜𝖊𝖗 𝖞𝖔𝖚 𝖜𝖎𝖙𝖍 𝖗𝖎𝖈𝖍𝖊𝖘.”
And so Werner became inspired,
...and shed a single tear.
...and in that tear
...was the root directory within which
....MuseScore was born.
And to join him,
...Terpsichore sent two angels:
Thomas Bonte
...and Nicolas Froment,
...with whom he founded a new company
...also named MuseScore.
Werner would remain focused on
...the architecture and product roadmap,
...with Thomas taking the role of CEO,
...and Nicolas organising the open-source contributors.
And now that I’ve mentioned open source,
...let’s spend a couple of seconds discussing that.
MuseScore is released for free
...under the second GNU General Public Licence,
...commonly called
'GPLv2'
This is interesting because
...GPLv2 is viral,
...which means that all future versions
and modifications licensed under it
...must remain that way,
...forever.
So,
...once GPL,
...always GPL.
This is to prevent companies from
...creating proprietary applications
...out of open-source projects,
...benefiting financially from the free work of others,
...while closing off access to the source code.
And due to this restriction,
...we can be certain of one thing:
MuseScore will always be free,
...and its project files
...will always be accessible to the public.
And that’s not to say it can’t ever make money.
It can,
...and that’s why it was acquired
by the Russian-based company
...Ultimate Guitar in February, 2018.
So, now its home is in Russia.
Hold on a second.
Hey, Shosty!
MuseScore has moved to the mother country.
What do you think of that?
"𝓘 𝓵𝓲𝓴𝓮 𝓲𝓽."
So before we go any further
...discussing what all of this actually means for the app,
...let’s open it up and see
...what the inspiration of Terpsichore has wrought.
Um
Oh, sorry.
Sorry, the skin doesn’t seem to have loaded.
How embarrassing.
Let’s just close it back down and try it again.
Oh.
Oh...
Huh...
Okay.
Now,
...I’m being completely honest here.
When I first loaded this app up,
...after hearing so much about it,
...my first reaction was,
"Are you serious?"
This almost instantly communicated to me
...that MuseScore was an amateur passion project,
...rather than a real app.
And this is surprising because,
...after spending quite a bit of time playing with it,
...I’ve found that the way it’s organised
...is actually really good.
But we’ll get to that later.
As it stands,
...this app looks like a dog’s dinner.
Well, that’s my opinion anyway.
I mean, what do you think, Shosty?
𝓤𝓾𝓾𝓻𝓰𝓱
𝓤𝓾𝓾𝓾𝓾𝓾𝓾𝓾𝓾𝓾𝓻𝓰𝓱
[pukes blood]
[̸̢̻̬̊̿͒p̴̣̰̞̐̍͝ư̵̫̤̙̅̄k̸̦͗̔̿ę̵͙̍̔s̴̤̞̀̽͛ ̶͉̘̲͗͊̽b̶̛̬l̶͠ͅo̵̬͐͛ȏ̶̤d̷̛͖̞̤]̷͉̑̓̓
[̵̡̻̹̻̞͕̾̋̂̑͆͒̂͐p̵͚͙̀̊͑̃̾̓̀̑͆̒u̸̡̩͖̜̣̬͚̰̗͚̤̘̎̓̐̂͐̅͝k̴̞̲̽̍̍͑͑͝è̸̬̥̗͕͓̘̙̂̓̾͊̐̿̕͝ͅs̷̡̺͙̜̺̪͉͓̝͂̏ ̷̭̺̞͓͒̑̍̓́b̶̨̢͇͚͎͉̳̤͇̘̃͋̐̒̿̈́́̋͌̀͜͝͝ͅļ̴̭̮̤̹͉̳̗͓͌̿̽̋̉̀́̄͗̚͠͠ͅô̷̧̮̖̭̣͕̦o̵̫͕̜͎͆̌̾d̴̛̝̘̯̒̽͜]̸̱͖̱̻̩̱͔̇͋̔̀̃̈́
[̷̢̨̝̻̲̥̤͉͚̹̘̝̪̑͑̏͋̎̾́̎͘ͅp̶̧̛̬̱̣͉̔͐̊̉̀̓͗̉̏͐͑͌̕͜͝ͅú̸̢̺̗̜̳̙͆k̶̩͓͕̲͙̩̟̻̍͌͌͐ͅe̴̤̰̩̖͔͛͒̇͘͜s̶̡̧̛̛̺̘̟̯͚̻̯͖̩̲̈̓͜ ̴̡̯̰̺̳̬̬̞̝͌͒̒́ͅb̴̡̺͒̿͝l̷̢̛̛̫͉̻͍̘̅̽̔̎̂̐̄̓̏̑̐̕o̸̺̼̬̯̲̣͇̎̎͊̈́͂͊͊͐̎͗̒̽̉̏̆͝ͅő̷̩͖͋̓́̈͂̉̕͝ͅd̴̢̨̢̯̱̦͍̞̲̣̼̽͘]̶̨̧̢̞̣̭̬̝̗̭̘͉͉̟̲̈́̒͂͑̌̇̏̈́̾̐
[̸̨̤̣̿p̵̧͎̯̯͖̯̩̟͎̥̦̦͔͎̼̭̝͙̘͇͚͗̂̅͛͐̌̈́͜ͅũ̵̦̮̩̼͚̣̺̗̪̟͈̩̳̥͓̥͎͍͎͂̓ͅk̸̨̛̰̟̗͙̭̀̾̂̉̈́̍̀͌͛ĕ̸͍͒̔̏s̵̛̙̳̱͈̺̥͎̖̘̭̼̒̋̀̂̓̃̈́̆̂̃͑͝͝͝ ̶̟̟̻̹̘̙̯̳̤͇̠̬͇͍̣͎̓̒̈́͒̉́̋̓͝b̷̢̢̧̥̰̝͈̘̼̣͕̹͚̱̼̈́̽̈́͛́́̒͒̀̀͑̿̆͒̄̀̿̚͜͝l̴̬̗̊͆́̅̒̇̓̿̀̈̑̓̅̄̽͝͠o̷̪̻̞̎̂͗̈o̴̢͉͉̫̝͎̝̗̜͎̪͚̐́̆̎̓̈́̃̅͑̌͐̑̊͋́͘͜͝d̴̞̜̦̞͚̺̺̞̬͙̤̱͇̳̗͖͂̑͘ͅ]̴̧̢̢̡͓̯͍̮̪̭̗͈͉͕̲͒̊̔̒
[̸̢̛̛̟̼̯̱̜̲̲̳̠̝̰̼͓̤̱̱̰͙̮̣̼͆̍͌̓̂́̓́̎͆̋͗̇̔̕͜͜͠ͅp̶̲̩̏̀̀́̿̈́̀̌͐̾͗̒̍̑̐́̂̓͆̊̓́̇̑̈́͘̚͘͠ŭ̷̔̾̾̈́̓̑͊͂̽͜͠k̷̢̡̧̦̜̥̟̱̲̟̟̣̲͖̠̣̠̥̞̟̹͚̀̇͒̇̂̈́̎̓̄̆͒͑̌́̕̕̚͝ͅȩ̵̢̖̭͎͎̟̫̮̗͔̘̜̒̔̾͛̓̄͒̈͌̏̽̒͊̆̿̚͠͠s̵̢̧̹̳͇̦̯̤̗̟̲͉̺͇͉̤̠͙̯͖̫̮̘̥̔͆̀̋͐͛̀̐̀̓͒̇̆̑͐̇͜ ̴̡̨̧̧̨̢̥̟͉̤̦͈̰̘̺̝͇̜͇̹̰̱̯͉̘̝̖͓͐́̊̄̔̐͒͋̾̀͛̋͆̾̋̈͝͝ͅb̵̛̜͇̝͇̝͉̤̫̙̈́͂̓̽͋̈́͗̂́͆̅̈́̋̊͛̈́̍͂̽͘̚͝l̷̢̨̨̢̛̠̣͙̹̤̲̳̞̦̰͚̰̮̩͇̜̱̪̪̹̪̘̰͍̞̼ͅơ̶̢̱͔̺̮͖̹͇̟̙̮͚̞͒͜o̶̧̢̡̧̨̨͈͕̭͍̦̭͙̼͇̳̗̪̗̠̰͍͆̏̉̓̾̉̅͜͜ͅd̶̨̯̟̤̻̓̆͊̓͠]̵̢̨̻͔̘̗̱̮̫̂̔͊͌́̈̍̓̃͋̏̓͂͆̊́̄̋͘͘͝͝͝͠
[̴̨̧̛̺̩̙̫̘͔̳̠̻̖͙̟͇̤͉͊̈́̿̍͗̐̂̈́͜͝͠b̸̡̨̛̛͚̟̺̳̙̰͕̖̝͔̺͚̬̳̟̭͕̞̘̰̌̀̏͐̇̊̔̓͋̐̍̋͐̽̾̑͂̑͒̒͜͝l̸̺͍̅̈̌̿͆͝ở̶̡̡͕̞̬̭̭͙͉̼̺̠̝̗̖͎̟͚̩̘̫͚̤̳̘̼͙̻̯͍̤̤̍̆͛͋̃͊̈́̒̏́̾̑́̍́̆̈́̒͐̋́̓͛̌̂̓̓̆͌̆̊̂́̓́̈́̐̅̚͘̚͘͜͝͠ȍ̷̧̢̨̨̡͈̼̟̬͖̮̲͓̙̙̜͍͎͚̥̝̳̫̤̫̠͎̯̱͇̪̳͓̮̣̱͓͈͍͎̽̐̔̊̉̽̇͗ͅͅd̶̨̛̛̄͒̏̃̋͗̈́̓̉͂̒͒̏̄̒̂̋̐͋̒̀͑̆̊̄͂̆͐͑́͗̿̀̾͊̑̏̕͝͠,̵̢̡̡̡̨̧̦̘̗͕̰̠̤͎̥͖̺͓̫̭͇̳̙͇̤̲̺̩͓̼̰͉̥̟͉̪͎̥̳͍̪̠͎͌̊̄͛̽͐̍̑̂̈͒̾͊̑͂̅͛͂͐̆̒́͌́̐̒̇͆̓̂̂̑̾͐̈́̈͑͆͋̂͊̕̕̚͜͝͝͝ͅͅ ̵̡̙͕̘̹̻̺̺͈̘̐̋̈̀̋̊͑̒̋́́̔̑̏́͗̄̈̓͗̀̈́̈̇̊̾̂̽͋͂̊̓̕͝͠͝b̴̢̫̪̣́̓͐l̶̡̢͉̦͇̪͙͈͈͍͎̤̭͚̝̘̣̮̱̥̘̗̩̗͖͓͇̯̪̫͇̟͍̼̙̪̜̏̍̀̄̐̿͗̊͐̐͑̄̿͒͋̑͌͑̏̅͊̿̿̏̄̚͜͠͝͝ớ̷̡̢̡̛͉͍̖̱͕̹͚̩̬̲͉̰̠͚̳̺̗̤̹̙̰̭̖͚̘̦͖̝̪̜̘̯̝͍̼̜̤̖͉̙͔̀́̐̋̀̑͐̈́̈̄̈́̃̀̉́͛̓̓̒͌̂̏͐̔̈́̽̈́͘͜ͅͅͅǫ̸̢̢̧̧̨̛̞̲͎̘͙͖͚̼̹̞̪̭͍̻̣̯̹̖̥̝͍̰̼̱͈͇͔̘͈̺̭͙̭̤͓̳͓̯̘͔̥̠̍̒͆͌̏̔̒̔̈́̇̂́͌̇̍̓̓̏̉͆̑͒͋̑̈̈́̅̅̆̀̿̕͘͝d̴̢̧̛̪̼͕̠̩̹̮̪̰̫͉̤̣͇̼̣̦̮̠̜͎͖̲̭͔͖̖̬̼͉̻̻̞̰̞͙̝͉̝̭̗̘̙͙̫͋͒̍́̒́̓̓͋͆̅̑̃́̈́̃̄́̇̌̈̽̉̿͑͌͐̍̈́̑͑̈̈́͘̚͘͘͘̚͝͝͝͝ͅ ̷̢̡̢̪̺̯̭͚̮̩͈͎̼̙̦̭̉̅͗̌͗͌̈́̄̿̓̿̓̈͜e̸̢̡̡͖̰̻̲̲̫͚̬̼̣̳̘͚̘̥̪͚̽͌͋͑͑͊̈́́̀̇̓͑̉̏͛̑̐͗̇̌́̏̄̊̆͒̇̊͆͆͌͘͘̚̚͠͝͝v̶̧̪͓͔͉̬̗̺̼͖̜̙̈́̊̐͗̾͂͂̊͆͝ȩ̶͔̖̖̮͍̓̓͛͗͑͒͐̋̅͊̃̆̈́̌͑̋̍̑͋͌̌̐̓̂̈̐̃͛̒̀̐̔͆̃̊̾̄͑̃̋̈͊͘͠͝͝͠͝ṙ̶̢̧̡̛̛͙̰̦͙̺̮̖̞̫̠̝̰͍͔͉̣̱̹͔͎͇̻͈͓͙̝̫̮̜̫̺͍̲̳̟̗̮̗̠͈̊̒̈̓͌̃͑͌̃͐̿͐̆̽̒̍̓̐͆̈́̆͊͜͜͝͝͠ͅy̵̡̡̧̢̛͓̥̲̳͙͉͈͎̬̠̬̭͓͖͙̲͕̼̭̩̳͔̪̦̗͉̗͖̘̥̼̞̖̗̰̺͉̌̄̈́͂̍͆̓́̈́̇̄̿͑͋̅͆͐̎́ͅw̵̢̛̠͙̳̗̼͖͚̠̹̘͔̗̫̩͖̭̟͉̠̗̩̬̞͉̥͇̲̱̲̦̬̽́̒̏́͌̒̓̄͊̐̓̋͌̈́̌́͋̎̃̈́͂̾͐͛̓̓́̕̚͘̚̕͜͝͝ͅḥ̵̡̢̢̡̤̤͓͉̦̗̥͔̱͉͇̦͔͔̳̬͚̞̼͚̪̬͇̲̯̝̺̮̪̲̱͚̱̩͕̼̋̾͂̑̂̓̈͜ͅé̷̢̛̜͔̰̘̩͖̱̱̇́̋̇̍̒̔͛̍͌̅̿̎̾̀͋̔͊͗́̈̆̅̃̅̓̑͋̄͌́̍̔͌͆͌̅͘̕͘͠͝͠͝͝r̴̡̢̛̛̛̛͚̤̱̜͔̺̮̜͖͚͚̮̖͎̤͉̰̯͎̭͍̮̱̀͑̂̂̄͗̎̍̀͗͌̑̾̅̈́͐͌̾͑͊̓͂̈́̄̑̽̈̈̉̀͘̕͜͜͝͝͠͝ͅe̶̲͖͇͂̐̉̄̀͂͝]̷̡̡̛̛̯̖͚̩͖̞͍̜̖̩̖͖̰̗̦͈͓̪̣̰͙̭̝̮͓͙͉̯͖̭̙̈́̎͛̽̃̀̀̆͌̊̈́̂͂̀͂̀̒̿̅̂͘͜
̴̛̲͈͎̻͍̲̙̏̽̓̋̇͆̽͊̍̈́͐͊̋̂́͐́̀̊̈̆͆́̓̈̀̌̾̈̑͛̓̾̊̎͋̕̚͝[̸̢̢̡̛̬̰̻̗̲̺̪̣̰̱͉̣̭̙̬̠̺̱̞̣̺̬̺̻͍̠̻̞͈̗̟̏̌͊͊̏̽̓͗͑̎̆͑̚͜͜͝ͅ ̷͉̆̉̔͊͒̒̊̆̈̾̅̓̿̓́̈́̋̑̊͒̒͂́̈́̈́͆̐͒̈́̎̚͠b̸̡̢̧̨̨̡̗̝̙̺̠̰̞̪̦̙̖̞̲̠͚͚͕̞̫͈̗̺͕̪̥̯̮̖̻̮̖̣͖͎͎͈͆̽̌͒̑͛̽͗͋͆͒̄͗̓̍̄̀̿́̈́͂͐͛́͒̀̔͆̿̚͝͠͝ ̶̙͔͚̪̠͙̠͓̊͑́̉̈́̄͑̓̈̍̿̍́͒͌̀́͋͑͋̎͆̅̿͐̓̋̈̐̈̄̕͠͝l̴̡̡̛̺̙̯̘̋̓̾ ̸̡̧̢̨̡̢̛̠̦̻̥͙͈͇͍̪̻͙͙̹̭͖̗̞̘̺̱̭̮̩̖̦̫̗͙̪̯̮̞̰͕̓̉́̓͒̅̇̈͐́̓̐̂̿͒̿͒͘͠ͅͅö̴̥̬̲̥̯̝͈̳́̔̎͛͂͂́͗̑̃́́͊̍̆̀̇͂̄͊̈́͆̌̓͌̃̓̄̅̕̚͝͝͝͝ ̴̧̡̤̯̫̤̙͇̄͜ơ̵̧̢̨̳̲̲͍̟͚̲̘̞̱̣͔̮͍̤͚̤͓̰̦͎̻̭̖̳̈̿̉̑͌͆̇̒͋͐̽͂̍̈̀̉͛̀͒̓͆͛̐͌̎̔͆̈́͝ͅͅ ̶̧̧̛̫̼̹̘̣͓̝̭̤̣̝̌́̍̊̇͒͑̈́̃͒́͋̏̓̉̅͌͒̅̏͑͆̀̃̀̏̅̎̄̔͐̅̓̐̓͐̕̚͘͜͝͠d̷̢̗̓̾͌̋̒ ̶̢̡̢̨̛̰̲͚̩̪̦̲̼̞̘̲̺̠̟̲̲̖̦͍͔̹̤̪̯͙͇̻̙̻͎̱͙̏̽͒̂̏͗̑̎̋̽̈̽͌̆̿́̈́͆͋͆̀͌̋͒̽̀̐̽̏̊̆͂̋͐͆̋̋̊̚͘̕͜͠͝͝͠,̵̡̨͉͖͎͎̣͎̤͇̯̫̩͓͖̣͈̬͖͙̫̤͉̯͇̬̰͕̫̰̬͖̲͕̭̼̰͈̙̼̹͕̥̾̑̇͗̂̄̈́̐́̍̓͒̈́͌̃̒̉̈́͆̏̽́̄̑̓̉̾͋̋́̍͗̊̆̆̈́̚̕̚̚͘͜͜͝͠ ̶̡̢̨̧̡̢̢̛̙̭̪͚͙͕̻̠̮̻͖̹͙͎̤͙͇̰̤͙̤̼̩͈͔͍̪͎̟̗̞͉̯̄͜͜ͅ ̷̧̡̧̨͍͓̝̠̦̱̪͎̖̲̤͙͖̦͚̬̰͇͙͔̭͔̜̣͊̐̔͂̂͊͐̉̆̍̾̀͒̍̈̑̓̓̐̈̀̇̿̓͗̐̏̇̉̃̾̇̒̀̈̀̋̿̇̍͂̚͘̕͜͠͝͝͠ͅ ̵̛̛̯͂̎̈̂̊́̓͗͐͋̔͋̉̃̎̆̉͛̐̒̔̒̏̄͂̿̌̾̽̌̔̈́̏̔̊̚̚̕̚̕͝͠͠͠͠b̶̢̎̇̿̀̄͋͌̈́̓̓̈́̊̔̆̂̒̚̚͝͝ ̴̲̠̅͌̾̐̂͗̇̓̇̀̆́̀̎́̌́̾͗̐́͑̐̋̍͌̾̂̐̅̕͝͠͠ĺ̸̢̢̢̡̨̧̛̰̪̦̬͕͈̟͇̻̣̣̟͕̪̞͈̗͉̼̜͙̬̝͉̮͎͎͕̻̘̗͓̼̳̥̄͗̓͌̽̍̆́̀͒̀͊̂͛͊̾̓̈́̍̓̽̋̊̃́̾͋̏̅̓̀̒̔̉̄̈͌̎̀̎̚͘͠ͅ ̷̧̲̖̖̳̭̳̜̦̻̞͚̤̖̰̤͕̟͕̙̖͉̔̈́̓̉̓͌͆̈́́͑̌̈́̄̇͋̈͐̓̀́̃̏̉́̅̀̐̾̕̚͘̕͜͝ơ̸̪̯̂̊͐̔̂̆̽̽͌̿̄̿́͂͂̈́̊̄̿̎̃̆̎̃̄̂̽̐̉̕͘̕͝͝ ̵̡̡̨̡͎̦̱͓͔͕̘̻̰̜̗̯͉̭̜͖̠̲̫͖͍̾̔͋̓̓͒͂̔͋̃̃͛̔͑̀̊͊̒̔̀́͒̉̊̓̕̚̚͝o̴̪͔͌̄̾͜͠ ̵̨̥̲͓͙̱̠̱̰͙̖͍̪̘̫̲̙͕͚̠͓̲̺̼̟̦̦̟̯̪̬̥̀́̌͋͊̋̈́͜͜ḋ̸̨͊͗̔̏̓̐̍̏̈́̋̀͐̀͘̚̕ ̵̨̛̛̛̛̙̦̖̮̩̳͓͉̤̹̣͈̱̥̣͚̐̈͊̆͑͐̈́̑́̽̿̒́̈́̉̓̄̍̇̎͊́̒̑̑͑̄͋͘͝͝ ̶̧̡̬̻̪̭̠̭͎̯̹͕̱̦̻͓͈͍̗͚͇̮̠̥͉̲̘̩͇̦̟̜̗̮̣̳̺̱̪͉͇̻͚͌̍̒͑̔̅̀͐͂͒̔͘͝͝ ̸̛͔̭̮̲̬̯̗͍̻͎̳̥͖͍͕͉͙̜̜̪̫͎̐̈́̀̎͑̽̀̃̎̀͑̿̊͘͜͝͠è̶̡̨̧̡͓͔̯̼̜̖̪̘̪̙̖̮̤̱̪̳̲̦̳̻̯̱͎͖̉̋̈́̎͂͆̈́̏͒̓͐́̃̒͛̌͘͝͝͝͝ ̸̡͈͍̼̯͔̝͈̥̤̬̭̤͎̞̫̦̻̜̩͕̞̖̥̞͚̫̗̣̜̟̀̐̌̔̅́͒̏̋̆͌̆̽̍̈́̈͊̚̕͘͘͘͝v̸̢̨̡̧̢͉͙̦̹͍̱̭̙͔̺͉͖̫̘̣͓̞̱͈̤͔̠̼̜̟͈̹͖̭̞͍̈͂̍͑̏̏͒́͐̉̕͘͜͜͝ͅͅͅ ̷̺̳͈̳̠̖̠̹͑̈́͛̓̂̊͐̎̂͊͜ȩ̶̨̡̨̛̬̮̥͔̼̳̞̺͕̭̱̰͖̺̦̮̜͔̪̭̘̠̲͇̺̟̯̗̤̗̳̻̯́́̽̆͊͑̍̋͆̿̑̈́̑͗͑̀̈́̆̈́̔͌̕͝͝͠ͅ ̴̨̧̧̛̣̤̲̭̪̲͈̹̼̮̬͔̩̺͙̦͈̞͚̮̏̎́̈́̉̽̋͂͑̽͐̾̃̾̾͜͝͠͝ͅṛ̶̟̣̜̦͍͔̰̞̪͚͍̫̮͎̝̗͓͚͉̘̜̥̬̗̦̮̦̥͍̂̂̕ ̴͙́͆̿̏̉̀̈̀̓́̆͒̉͘̚͝ỳ̵̧̱̣̞̳̹̻̗͈̞̤̖̥͂̈̈́̃̂͋̿͗̀̒͝ͅ ̴̨̡̛͉̟̺̺̪͉̣̘̩̣͕̟̜͙͎̞̝̦͖̟̠͉̗̬̪̗͖̼̮̗̦̬̩̣̜̙̠̣͈͕̈́̏̏̏͑̎̊̈́̀̇̈́̀͛̀̈́̈̒̚w̵̬̟͈̻̑̿͛̆̍͗͋́̽̽̅͑͒̾̂̽̓̈̇̉̆̏́̓͑̎̎͆̓̈́̕̚̚͝ ̶̛̟͈̘͔̩͎̤͑̇́͑̈̏̐̆͂̅̃̅̈́̂̔̑͒̈́͌̈́́́͒̉͆̕͝͝h̷̨̡̨̳̙͇̣̬͖̤̞̗̠̭̺̯͉̪͙̱̼̙̞͚̰̳̱͉̮͈͇͚̙̹̠͚͕͔͍̮̬͔̮̉̒̂̀͗̇̈́̑̉͋̈́̉́͂̌̑̽̒͊͊̓̑̑͗̑̋͗̾͜͜͝͝ ̴̢̡̡̢̳̭̺̱̰̫͚̮̲̰͔̫̹̤̗̖͙̹͖͓͉̜̯̯̮͓̰̤͙͙̯͓̥̘̽̓̄͑͜e̶̝͇̰̲͙̟̘͎̗̗͛̆̈́̒͐̊̅̿́̿̑̽́͝͠ ̴̘͚̜̤͎̮̗̩̫̥͖̲͌̈̔͆͑̎̒͋̐̒̌̈́̒͌̀̇̈́̈́̋̈́̃͊̿͆̑̏̉̒́́͑̃̔̚͜͝r̸̢̢̢̢̡̧̯͕̮̺͍͙̼̣̲͍̙̹͇̯̬̞̝̳͈̘̳̰͖̣̭̼̺̙͈̗̳̙̒́̀͛͗̈̍̓̓͗̈́̉̾̋̑̒̿̅̈́̀̀͑̀̕̚͝͝͝ͅ ̴̛̞̹̺̲̫̖̠̩̦͈̦̜̺̩̪͚̀̋̀͐̈́̓͑̀̒̿͑̿͐̿̔͋̎̀͊̎͐̏̑̇̀̀̾̏̚͘̕͜͝͝͠ȩ̵̧̧̡̛͕̳͍̳̠͔̭̞̲̫͓͓̼͍̗̘̺͕̣̠̗̺̤̲̻̏͂̿͒́́͊̈́̌͌͋̈́̊̍̀̆̂̽̃̌̅̊̈́̀̀́͊́̒̑͆̑̈́̒͐͐̀͋̾̚̚̕̕͜͠͝͝͝ͅ ̷̢̛̩̩͈̟͉͓̠̻̣͕̳̹͉̼̒̽̈͝ͅ]̸̡͈̪̦͕̗̻͕̼͖̹̘̭̦͚̼̫̤̦̻̘̰͕͇͓̜̝̥͕̮͌̎̒̌̎̈̈́͂̔̅͂̑̀̏̑̒̉̾̉̇̊̒̈́̆̈́̈́̓̏̈́́̅̽̚͝͝͝͝
̸̫͔̯̔̊̀̐̄͋͒̽̊̇̇̐̒̅̔̌̾̎̀̾̈̀̆͑̂͛͊̒̎͌͗̄͂̉̕͝͠[̷̢̢̪̳̭̤̦̣͖̠̙̟͎̦̺̥͚̦̘̬̑̓̒̍̑̇̓͋̓̔͘͠͝ͅｂ̵̡̧̡̨̝͕̹̭͙͓͍̪̪̺̳̬̖̞̦̪̻̞̠̳͐̈́̿̎̓̓̑̑͗͒̒̄̂̅̈́͛̇͜͝ͅͅͅｌ̷̧̢̨̧̙̖̫̯̞̮̻͖̙͓̰͖̥̤͇̞̰̼͚̝̭͚͕͕̫̯̠̻͓͙̯̠̆̓̾̈́͌̋̂͆͋͗́̃͊͛͑̈́̀̍͂̒̀͗͌̽̉̄̀͝͝ｏ̴̡̛̛̳̞͖͙͚̫̬̥̮̟̯̳̱̺̯̖͙̤͔̭͕̜͈́͊͗͐̊̉̑͗̈́́̃́̑̔̏̏̿̓͐͑̈̈́̑̔̅̽̐̐̎́̕͘ͅｏ̴̢̧̢̨̛͈̪̖͉̘̥̳̖͈͇͔̥̞͚̮̫͙͓̠̳̣̖̙̟̹͍̬̗̟̗̯̩̀͌̾́̈́͗͌̃̿̇͒̂̑̿̈́́̈́̐͛̅͘̚͜͝ｄ̵̧̨̧̫̖̼͇͕̣̝̩̮̲̱̪̜̈́͛͜，̴̡̢̨̨͚͍̼̫͇͕̣͕̟͖̪̪͍͖̟͙̰̥̳̱̊̌̓͛͒̚͝ ̸̢̧̡̨̭̰̩̟͕̜̻̮͎̜͓̳̼̳͇̟͈̳̟̥̝͔͔̥͉̘̣̝̟̈́̀̅͋̍̌̐́̾̔̓̓̄̽̋̈̅̽̀̎̄́̈̃̉͛̌̇͛̀̌̆́͑̀̑̃͗̇̈́̓̚͘͘͜ͅͅｂ̴̧̧̢̡̭̰̞̜̝͚̱̦̜͈̫͓̜̣̞͎̣̱̯̝͝͝ｌ̵̡̨̛̤̟̫̭̙͚̤̟̳͇͎̰̦̲͕͖̗͍͚̱͉͚̹̝͚̞̬͈̘͓̣͍̜̓̏̿̃̐͋̊͋͆̍́̇͂͌̏̌̋̐̃͆͆̂̂́̄̌̒̚͘͜͠͝ͅͅｏ̶̧̛̙̯̮̬̓̈̌̊́̒̇̋̓͌̅́̏͑̈́̄́̇̾̽̊͒͌̂̅̍͗͘͘̚͝͝͝͝ͅｏ̶̧̢̫̫̖͇͍̠͖͚͉̘̼͕̮̗̼͉̥̹̼̳͇̬͓̭͙̟̻̹̺̙̦̬̳̖̖̱͋̑̅̀̇̆̈́̔̄̽̏̓̅̈́̏̄̉͊̑̐̾̃̒̈́̃͗͛̈̀͝͠͝ͅｄ̴̢̨̤̠̝̼̦͇̤̟͇̗̟͔̠̟̲̦̜͇͎͚̼̻̥̣͉̺̣̲̪̳̝̝͈̀̅̊͊̋̍̉̋̉̌̆͊̓́́̌͆̉͆̒̍͆̈̑͗̈̈́̈͋͆̅̈́͑̄̉͆̇̉̚̕͘͜͝͝ ̵̢̢̨̡̛̜̪͖͚̗̩͙͎͈͓̭̝̩̱̹̳̠͍̳̜͍̲͓̀̀͆̔̋͒̿̋̈̓͗̈́̑̔͊̎͑̈̈́̎̒́̎̅̈́͐͒̑̊̀̓̽͋́̕̚̚͘͜͝ｅ̸̡̢̢̡̛̰̝͕̟̠̭̘͔̬͔̮̬̣͓͕̥̖̦͇̪͊̾͋͒͋͐͛̀̀̅̔͂̃̉̇̈́̈́́̊́̑̈̇͊̔́̔̐̐́̂̒̓̔̈́̕͘͠͝ͅｖ̸̨̢̢̨̜̪̮̣̠̝̩̳̖͔̘̺̙͔̦̠͍̥͈̪͈̳̻̙̮̻͙̲͇͔̲͖̻̙̏̈́̾̓̓͗̾̈́̊͑̃̇̅͌̂̇̃͋̎̉͑͒̂̄̌̉̊̊̈́̅̆̈́͑̇̚͝ͅｅ̸̢̢̡̨̧̢͔̺͈͔͉̞͈̣̘͓̮͎͓̖̹̦̞̟̜̳͕̟̬̥̥̼͇̥̔͑̄͌̊̽̍͗̇͂̐͗̽̑̏̈́̈́͗̓̅̚͘͘͜͜͝ｒ̵̧̧̛̛̤̩̣͍̱̞̭̥̘̥͇̯̖̥̙͇̜̝̮̱̟̘̤̦͙͉̗̹̞̤̯̗̤͊͐́̓̿̋͂̒̉̋̂̆̎̌̔̎͋͋͂̈̊͒͌͌̈̏͌̽͌̃̈̐̑͐̚̚̚͝͝ｙ̶̛͖͓͈̼͇̼̩̝̮͎̪̠̺̟̠̼͈̮͂͛̿̇̈́͋̂̌͊͂̽́̽̌̉͒̋̾̓͛̍̑̊̇͛̆̄̈́̈́̄̉̓̽̍͑̑̄̑̋͋͒̔̌͘͝͝ͅｗ̸̦̣̹̐͛̂̓̋̓͐͒̋̏̊͑͂̈́̓̊̍̾̋̈́͛́̄͆͗́̓̕͘ｈ̷̛̪̱̗̳̯͙̲̼̟̠̞̻͉̄̌̉̌̈́̏̓̓̔͌̇͊̌͐̓̾̐̂͊͐̎̔̄̏̈́̊́̏͛̇̃̃͋́͌̑̐̔͜͝͝͠͝ｅ̴̧̢̧̧̛̛̛̙̭͖̑̑̍̌̽̀̀͐̈́́͌͗͂̐̒̿̑́͒͑̐͆̒̀͂͛͌̂̈́̌̿͐͐́̕̚̕͠͝͠͠͝͝͝ͅｒ̴̢͇̞̳͔̣͉̝̬͉͓̮̠͇̜̰̩̥̭̪̮͇̹̫̜̬̲̇͗̍̔̀̈́̆̋̀́̔͂̈́̽̔̈͊̌̋̑̈̇̏̔̓̎͘͜͝ͅͅͅｅ̷̧̨̡̨̛͇͍̲͕̩̥̯̪̮̬̜͚̬͖͓̫̺̞̗̲͈̫̫̥̗̗̖̫̂̒́̈́͌̈́̍͆̈́̒̍͊̾́̆̉̔̏̒̇̊̈̊͆͆̇̆̒̏́̒̽̚͘̚͘͝͠͠ͅ]̸̧̧̧̧̨̛͍̝͕̬̩̰̱̩̟͙̬͔̠͖̪͚̞͚͖͇̰͎̰̑̉̓͊͒̃̓̌͗͌̒̇̈̽̚͝ͅ
̶̢̺͉̱͕̟̺̣͙̖̘͈̫̫̪̯̬̯͔͇͕͖̦͉͉̹̰͗͌͐̇͂̈́̂̅̿̈́̇͐̊͜͝ͅͅͅ[̶̡̡̡̨̨̢̢̨̧̛̛̫̳̼̩̳̮̦̳̤͓̼̪̫͕͎̲̬̦͍̲͉̪̫̹̮̣̮̙͔̘̤͉̳̙̤̦̻̻̠̞̞͇̬͎͕͈̃̾̀̂̓̐͋͗́͛̒̈́̇̏̚͜͠ ̷̨̨̛̱̬̦̪͈̟̩̼̝͔͉̪͖̻͕̰̣̽̎̊͗̋̇͂̿̑̈́̃͊̋̒͘̕̕͠ͅs̴̨̨̧̠̭͔̰̬̙̘̭̖̼͚̫̺͚͎͔̙̊͊̑͗̉̐̋̍̑̆̄̌̾́̈́̀̈́́̄͊̆̄͛̄̏͐̓̀͐̉̽̽͌̌̄͑̑́͆̌͂̈́̋͛̇̈̚̕̚͘̕͘̕͠͝͝i̵̡̡̧̢̛̘̮͙̬̼͙̜̪͓͙̪̙̼͚͔͕̬̖̠̥͕͚̙̣̘͓̭͍̞̩̮̬̜̟̗̣̖̮̠̰̯̩͕̦͇̝̪̟̫̗̝̞͔̟̪͖͒͒̂̓̋̏̃̆̚͜͜͠͝ͅͅb̶̧̢̡̨̡̛̙̤̖̟̜͎͚̟̯͈̮̣̼̩̜̘̥͕̺͇͕͎̦̳͉̫̩̖̅͊͊͐́͆͆̾̍̐͗̊̃̏̂̏̉͑̆̌̍̋̆͋̃͑̊̈́̅̍̈́̄͛̈̀̐͒̕͘̕͘͜ͅe̷̡̢̡̧̧̢̛̛͕͇͚̹̮̗̗͙͔͈̙̗̠͇̜̣̠̤͎̯̘͈̹̞͕͍̘͖̟͙̼̯̠̭̯̮̩̞̥̭̤̬͑̃͗̄̑͊́̏̈́͑͒̈́̓́͜͝͠ͅl̷̢̧̡̨̧̨̡͇͉̙̲͔̪̼̻̥̜̥̲͎̠̜̩͓̲̦̰̲̭̯̥̘̘̞̹͇̲̥̱͎̟͖̼̼͐͂̽̒̇̆̈̑̊͑̚͜ͅi̸̡̞̜̥͓̭͎̞̠͈̹̞̝̫͕̺̮̤͉͎̟̝̝̩̙̻͙͈̮͎̙̙̞̝͓̻͉̋͗̌̔̆̎̏̈́̅͆̄̈̊̊̐̀͐̈́̒̽͐͌̀̽͗̅͒̔̌̈́͑́̐̀̂̍͊͆̈́̂̂͂́͋̃̀̅̽͘̕͠͝͝ừ̴̡̨̡̨̧͖̲̙͍̟̪̗̼͇͉̱͔̮̲̜̹̮̰͚̜͙͚̺̜̗̝̫̦̯̠̻̞͉̦̘̥̳̟̺̪͉͕̺͓͉̮̫̙̯̘̥̜̥̙̿̄̈́͒̓͗́͐͐̈́̀́͛̑̑̌̎́̿̈́́̈͊́̕̕̚͘̚̕͘͜͜͜͝ͅͅs̴̡̧̮͙͚̦̭̺̦̲͈̺̹̥͚̏͊͂̽̋̋̍̆͆͑̌̆̃̽̄͆̅̈́̉̀̀̄̔̆̐͋͋̇̅̿̈́̃̀̅̒͑͋̆̈́͌͂̉͊̉͛̐̂̍͂̄̃̅̚͘͠͠͝͝͝͝ ̸̢̡̡̨̢̡̛̺̘͔̝̣͍̘͚͕̣͇̜̯̬̰̮͈̝̳̙͍͉͇̘̥̫͇̲̖̩̭̦̲̪̼̎̊̎͒̐͋͊̽̐͑͑͐̎̎̒̓̀͗͐͒̈́̓́͋̐̑͛̍̋̈́̅̏̾̑̋̾̄͗̑̇̅̄̚̚̕͜͠͝͝⍰̸̨̡̨̢̡̛̛̣̘̝̫̗͓͖̦̦̝͈̙̜̻̗̝̣̱̝̼̘͈͇̣͉͍͖͍̬̮̹̼̜̥̼̘̫͙̺͉͚̲̲̪̗͉̟̣͖̮̺̳̐̂̂̑͐̀̎̐̃̔͂̊̒͗̌̒́̏̍̾̐̄̈́̂̊̉̅̓̓̾̒͆̈́́̀́̉̔͋̀̀͆̏͊̕̕͜͝͠͠ͅͅ⍰̷̢̼͓͍͕̑͒̑͆̌̀͂̄͛̾͑̌͜͠͠ ̴̧̨̛̬̰̻͙͓̱̻͕̥̦̦͕͈̦͇̝̺̫̖͓̙̣͇̭͉̮̙̓͌̌̾̌̌̋͂̈́̓͐͑͋̾̆͆̓̈́̃͛͊͌̆͑̄̋́͊̿͐̍̅͋̈́͗̈͐̚̕͜͝͠͝͝Ȅ̷̫̎͋͒͑̓͐R̴̨̡̼͈̭̤͈͚̫̪͕̙̼̦͋̈́̄́̈͂͌͒͊̾͗̌̕͝͝͝R̶̡̢̢̞̖̬̞̰̘̬͉̟̟̙͖̘̺̬͖̣̬̻̪̰͙͉̲̝̃͑̀̽͐͋̇͆͒̒͋͂̄͋͝ͅƠ̵̢̛̛͖̱̲̞̼̥̹̟̥̙͇̘͙̱̥̲̦̹̤̦̭̲̣͓̲̜̤̿̒͗̏́̿̐͊͑̔̎̀̇̌̅̏̉̈̊̆̃̉̂̊̈́͒͂̈́̎̒͆̐́̽̓̌̄͋͑̋̓̃̋̒́̕̚̕͘͘̚̚͘͝͝͝͝ͅȐ̷̢̧̢̨̢͇̭͉̞̩͚̖̳̟̖̟͔͚͎̫̮͚̣͈̣̬͍̳̲̥̩͎̗̠̠͇̲̗̙͊͂͐̈́̆̚ͅͅ ̵̢̧̨̖̻̭͔̯͔̩͍̰̘̙̼͔̙̭̺̪̺͇̬̙͔̫̘̱̬͉̯̺̬͎͇̜̻̼̮̲͉͙̥̺̭̣̻̬̜͉̹͔̐̓͊͂̍̿̅̌̃͂̾̂̈́͂͂͑̆̈̏̈́̾͗͂̈́̈́̍̔͊̈́͌̈͘͘̕͘͠͠͠͠͠͠ͅ⍰̵̡̢̨̛̛̙͕̫͍̦̖͍͇̙̭͖̩̫̗̮̆͑̓͂̓͊̈́̄̃͋̃̈̊͗̄̋̓̐̓̽̂̃͛̎̔̏́̅̈̅͊̍̄̒̾͌̆̈́̀̆͊̐̏͗́͛̌͆̉͐͆͐̄̚̚͘͝͝͝͝͝͝͝ǫ̵̡̢̡̛̬̣̫̻̠̥̦̱̗͔͓͓̼͖̣̼̰̞̖̠̗̥̠͔̣̥̹̰̱̜̭͓̳̯̠̮͕͚̜̣̰͓̂̓͛͌̊̂̀̀̍̇̇̓̉̒̓͑͐́̕̚̕͜͜͝ͅ⍰̸̡̡̨̮̤̯̣̥͚̜̬̣͈̖̟̯̫̦͙̗͉̣̻͖͇̣̩̮̜̠̤͓̱̦͎͙̺͉̹̺̤̺̹͔̲̞̲̳͉̠̫͎̲͎̞̬̪̲̞̈͋͗͆̚͜ ̵̨̡̡̺̫̙̥̮̱͎̝̜̠̪̟̘̩̥̳͇̦̠͕̦͑̊͊͌̐̅̓͐̔̌̋͌́͋͗̽̐̋͑̿̾͑́͗̈́͂̂͑̏̈́͐̈́̑͌͌́̊͛̒̎͛̈̋̉̃̃̚̕̚͝͠͝ͅŏ̵̡̨̨̢̧̧͚̱̠̭̖͖͚̦̦͔̣̠͔̝͈̰̦̬̻̘̩̳͉̪̠̟̰̙̩͇͇̜̥͓̪̼̪͓̖̙͉͈̯̼̲̣͍̪͚̞̮̲̻͕̮̹͙̈́̆̀̊́̇̄͒͂̏̽͑̉̊̓̾͆̉̉̆̏̕̚͜͜͜͠ͅ4̴̡̨̧̡̛̛̛͓̗̰̺̭͉͎̤̞̗͈̝͓̯̜͎̻̩͍̠͇͎̞͕̫̭̫̗̥͈͉̗̀̿̈́̂͑͛̽͐̎̊̽̍̑̃̔̇͗̋̃̀̊̈̈́̂̽͌̒̋̂̀̆̔̓̓̉̔͆̒͊̆̄͆͛̒͘̚̕͜͝͠͝͠0̷̢̛̦̰͎̤̮̝̹͍̺̤̠̞̩̫̫̭͇͉̰̞͉̬̝̜͙͔̼͚͖̣͙́͒͆͐̾͊́̓̔̍́̓̌̾̋̃̋͊͘͘̕͜͜͝4̸̪̠̥̗͓͇̰̞̯͇͖̏̃̅͒́͊̊͒ ̵̧̧̨̡͇̺͇͔̖̦̥̞͇̳͇͍̲̙̬̞͎͙̘͍̠̩̦̻̞͓̄͆͋̊͐̈́͒̔͋͂̈͋̽̇͌̄̇̆̔̋͂̌̍̏̆̍̄̃̀̐̅͊͑͛́̋̚͘͘͝͠͝͠͝͠Ę̶̧̢͔̘̰̹̳͔̺̞̟͇̙̜͙̦̥̩̘̈́̄̔̍͛̌́͆̅̎̈̅̒̔̅̌͗̅̀̽̇̾͛̍͗͊̌͆̿̎͘͝R̶̢̢̢̢̛̰͓̬̖̙͍̯̥̗̥̫̬̜̝̫̫̙̥̪͍̗͉̲̤͇̭̮͙̝̣̭̫̭̳̖͈͔̮͓̮̦͕̈́͛̓͛̃͋̓̀̂̃̀̈́̈́̽̊̏̓̿͛́̂̌̈́͌͐͆̏́̔͊͂͂͑̒̍́͆̌̓͑̈́̐̒̐͂̌́͝͝͝͠͝R̸̛̹̟̍̊̈́̉̏̂͆̒̓̉̓͐̒̽̌̊̾͒̋́̃̆̾̄͘̕͠ͅr̷̡͓͕͔̗̼͉̭̝̣̞͖͍̦̱͔̼͇͚̗̤̠̈́́͛̊͋̾́͒̃́̾̇͑͌̉̀̈̀͊̓̽͆͌̿̎̀́̀̀͛̃̿̈́̌͐̃̊͋̿͆̋͛̓̅̇̆͌̎̉̈͑̋̓̒̄̈́̑́̚̚̚̕̚͘̚̚͘͜͝͝͠ͅö̶̡̝̹͕̬̙̦̲͉͍͎͈̳͎̼̩̱͚̳̰̩̮̤͓̺̤͙̜̭̲̣̜̭͙̬̱̙͍̰͙̞̼̱͚͚̝́̔͊̇̃̀̂̉̾͊̀̏̌̈́̈͆͂͗̂͐͐̿̈͂̔̾͊̚̕̕̕͜͝͠͠ ̷̡͈̺̥̤͎̹͐̃̇6̵̧̡̧̨̡̢̼̝͖̮̜̯̰̥̝͎͎͎̜̱͔̣͎͓̹̟̦̰̬̮̮͕̦̯͔̺̜̼̯̭͚̘̘͓̩͖̬͓̮̳̭͉̭̫͇̝̥̪͎͒́̈́̒̑̍͌́̀͂̉̇͑̈́̀̀̽̍̏̅̉̈̚͜͝͠ͅͅͅͅ6̷̡̮̘̦͖̮̣̋̊͆̂̇̓͒̑̌͝ͅ6̷̨̧̡̛̛̛̜͚̻͖̥̺͚̣̭͖̖̝̭͉̼͔̯̦̘͔̜̪̞̜̙̞̠͙̠̻̟̮̣̼̦̟̺̯͎̩̺͎͙̳̫̯̬̥͉̍̈́͌̑̑̈́̍͂̀͌́̉͋̈́̑̈́̍̒͂͗̓̋̓͛̍͐̔̍̐́̈̔̚͜͜͜͜͝ ̸̡̡̢̬͈̲̜͇͖͎͔̥̟̰̩̥̖̖̟̙̖̄̽̔̓͜ͅ0̵̧̡̢̨̡̧̢̩̙̦̬̯̥͇̦͎͙̪̰̳̝͔̱̙͍̰͍͚̣̥̱̟͓̝̫̮̼̥̪̤̹͉̘̭̩̜̟̩̘͖̖̤̙̖̟͓̫̱̖̙̖̪̞͊̾̔̋̋̈̓́̂̍̂̐̿͛̔͛̃́̓́̈́̋̏̈́̅͛̓͊̆͊̆̄̈́͗̇͗̂͑͌̒̕͜͜͝͝ͅͅư̷̛̩͈̬̈́̈́́̿̅̊̽̎̓̍̒̇̐̍̅̍͋͂̂̑̓̊̀̄̓́̐̒͗̏̈́͌̍͗́̈͒̔́͗̀̑̃͌̔̇̐̾͊̉͋̕̚̚͘̚̕̕͝͠͝͝w̶̺̄̍̌̈́̅͂̋͘9̸̨̨̧̢̦̫͈̦̝͓͈̝̰̝̙̣̲̬͔͚̗̟̯̠̰̩̬̠͍̮̜̮͕̱͓̝͕̦̰̣̖̯͉͆̿̍̄̀͂̌̆̓͗̓̍͐́̋̓̏̈́̀̉̈̈́̽̐̌̌͋̾͂̿͒̋̈́̊̄̇͋̆̔͂͆̑̈́̈́̆͑̔̍̈́̽̉̈́̈́̊̿̊̉̒͘͘̕͠͠͝͝͝͝͠͝ ̶̡̢̡̢̧̢̧̡̛̰̹̪̳̩̖̖͎͍̟̺̲͖͙̯̥̟̞̱̖̟͇̻̖̺̮̤̪̺̯̩̠̫̰̤̦̥͕̰̺̞͙͖̼̝̗̟͚̝̝͉̝̊͛̂̇̊̀͆̿̈́̀́́͂̿͂͋̈́̾̈́̈́̒͌̇̓̅̈̓͗̔̚͜͠ͅŵ̵̢̧̧̧̡̢̛̜̜̝͚̦̖̞̠͇̪͙͇̥̫͖͈͍̥̦͓̩͉̠̣̮̘̞͚̻̜̳͉̤͔̠̟̯̪̩̤̬̼͕͍̿̇̈̔̔̉̄́̾̃́̔͌͋̈́͌́̾̓̒̎̆̐̿̋̈́̐̿̄̓̀̒̇͌̈͌͂͘̕̕̚͝͠ͅq̴̢̧̨̡̛̼͔̜̪̲̼͚͎͖̠̯̩̘̹͈̗̘͙͕̫̘̹̬͉͙̫̼͎͍͉͈̹̤͔̖̹̯̻̻͙̲͚̟̼̹̼͉̰̞͙̩͖̖̟̣͉̯̋̎͋̓̀́̈̿͒̃̀̊͆͊̏̄̐̈́͊̂̔̑̈́̍̄̾̅͒̂̇̀͆̃̃̓͐̐̆̈́́̑̎̂̿̐̿̔̾̇̿͘͜͜͝͝ͅͅt̷̛̮̺̪͑̈͐͆̉̓͑͂͗̆̑̏̆̕͘̕ ̷̢̧͙̺̪̪̼̘̦̪̜̮̪͔͈̗̰̭̟͍̹͍͕̞̥̺͚̺̜̙͈̳̝̱͔̝̙̝͓͆͆̃̐̂̏̀̄͐͑̏̌̈́̽͛͌̓̾̈́̌̄̓̌̂͂̽̎̓̓͋͑̀͑̋̆͌͌͐̕̚̚̚͜͝͝͠͝ͅͅp̵̢̛̛̪͉̞͔̳̫̜̩̌͒̑͑̊͛͂̊̒̓̆̌̉̄̈̌̀̂͋͂̓̇͆̓̃̒͘̕͠͠͠ͅͅ ̴̨͕̜͎̻͚͓̱̤̠̹̩̯͇͔̹͇̜̱̯̘̖̫͇̪̯͙͎͍̥̥̥̦̮͙̺̱͖̯̹̭̪̭̫̠͖̩͉͋͆̀̈́̾̿͗̐͆̽̈́̈́̆̎̍̑̌͊̋̑̀͌͋̒̋̂͛̎̄̏̎͑̔̕̕͝͠ͅơ̶̲̦̬̥͓̙͔̠̫͇͍̬̗̰̼̤͖̗̺̹̈́̉̈́́̈́̈́̓̏̂̑̇̄̍̃̍̍̎̃̔͗̀̑̎͗̆̀́̓͘̚̕̚͠͠͝i̶̢̜͓̬͙͍͔̗̼̮̓̉̏̊͐́͆͒̋̿͋́͂̌̓͌̓͆̔͆͒̓̑̀̒̓͘̕̕̚͘̕̕͜͠͝͝͝͠⍰̸̧̧̢̨̡̡̡̧̨̛̱̲͚̗̯̲͇̰̦̯̥̹̝͍̫̪̟͚̖͇̼̦̲̫̼̟̱̟̘͎̙̩̣̣͎̦͙̜̖̤̗̖͎̼̲̲͚̠̲͙̝̀̆͒͐͗̀͛͐̓͌̾̚͜͝͝ͅͅͅi̷̛̛͔͌̊̋̊̊̎̔̍̍́̒̀̏͂͛̾͒͐̔̍̔̑̓̈́̔̌̃̑̓̍̒͂̀̾̇̍̍̽̍̅͗͂̌̒̐̈͊̓̏̒̚̕̚̕͘͘͝ ̶̢̨̧̢̛̛̛̩͈̺̯̫̝͙̬̳̬̼̗͇̹͕̣͙̞͉͍̤͔̜̰͕̯̣̝̳̬̹͚̗̻̱͕̤͉͓̖̙̞̜̺̙̙̣͔̝͚̥̥̦̰͍̱̝̭̳̺̓́̄̋̀̀̉̓̄̈́̊̑͑͐̈́̾͐͑̊́̀̿͊͗̓̾̅̓́̋́͗̀̋͌̐̄̎̿̑̏̕̕̚͜͜͠͠ͅd̶̡̧̨̧̢̧̨̹̱̱̞̺̣̤͕̰͔͚̬̟̻̩̲̺͚̼͎͕͚̲͎͈̣̻̙̖͉͉͎̯̩̬͉̰̲̲̘̖͕̻̜͚͐̓͂̍͗̐̍͊́̒̐̽͛́̀͋̓̀͆͌̔̾̇̋͛͒̎̍̒́̅̔̑̐͊̏̇̿̒̊͒̈̄̓͒́̏̀̎̏̒̈́̃̑̓̒̀̃̌́̏̌̕̚̕̚͘͘͘͝ͅͅş̵̖̥̖̼̽̆̀̆͂̊͌͆̿́̎͑͊͑̓̐͆͗̑͐͒̎̈́̽̌͋̎̅̄̐̐͒̕̕̚͠c̷̢̡̧̡̡̜̤͍̬͈̩̝̞͇̗̟̟̫̫̣̥̪͍̩͙̦̫̩͙͖̙͎̗̺͓̥̬̖̯̭̟͍̟̺̙̖̘͉̱̐̈͒̉̒̑̔̎̚͝ͅḩ̶̨̧̡̨̛̛̩͉̣͖̘̭̰͇̩͔̭̱͚̩̖̻̦̮̖͚͖͓͚̬̯̹͔̖͓̰͇͕̬͙̻͕̺̱̭̜̫͆̓̓͑̉̈̆͛͑̌͑̐͆̋́͒̍̔̑͌͑͛̿̿̋̎̓̔̋̊͑̉̒̑̇̑̀̐̈̈́̽̆̔̈́̓̊̎̒̂͘͝͠͝͝͠ͅ ̸̨̨̢̧̢̡̮̦͔̰̮̱̺̤̺͚̮̦͖̱̥̞̣̫͇̲͉̭̬͚̻̳̥̱͇̜̱̥̙̱͚͍̮͖̟͖͉̥͕͍̰͇̠͇͙̣̮͖̹͖̘̪̻́͋̈̈́̓̉́͑̇̾͋̔́̋̀̔͋̍̅̃̓͗̄̊̕͘͘̕͜͜͜͜͝͠͝͠d̶̡͓͚̥̲̘̥̺̳̙̟͇̰̜̖͍̦̹̮̬͘͜͜s̶̢̧̡̨̛̱̼̠̥̺̲̥̱̦̦͙̼̹̬̘̝͕̼͈͕̝̱͙͕̲͙̲̼̣̮͕̙̀̃̒͛͐̂́̒̈́̓̇̂̌͑͒̈́͋̈̔̽̌͗͂͗͒͊̈́͋͂̕͘̚͜͠͝͝͠ͅc̵̩̠̍̉̾̿̏̆̐̔̿̇͂͒̃̆͋̃̓͛͛͊̅̌̿̈́̈̎̅̃̉̐̀̔̀̌́͒̒͐̋̐̾͒̿͝͠͝͠͝h̴̨̧̧̡̧̹̠̘̱̹͍̲͇̣̠̖̳͎̙͚̭͙̘͓̣̺̖̝̙̫̟̭̦̗̼͎̟͉̰̲̜̜̝͖̹̯͓̬̦̮̯̪̽́̃̆̒̎͆̕͜͜͜͜ͅͅ ̴̡̡̡̛̛̞͎̹̳̩̳͔̱̦͚̱̝͔͉͓̤̼̼̦̠͓͚͕̳̩͓̺̪̖̳̅̍̆͗̄̒̑̀̾̽̎͛̊̈̑̊́̎̉̆̆̈́̾̊̇̀̒̔͛̽̈́̔̾̀͒̈́̈́͘̚͘̚͘͜͠͝ͅͅd̷̡̟̣̠͕̠̹̖͎͎̗̼͔̟̰̙̬̤̰͚̮͖͔͉̘͕̝̟̈́͂͛̉̐̔̈́̋̄̀̓̈̒͂̅̈́͑̽̂̓̍̓̄̿̕͝͝s̵̨̛̛̩̼̙̖͓̱̟̖͎͙̪̼̪͎̱̖̣̟͍̓͋́͊̈́͌̂̃̾̎͋̾̿̀́̌̉̂́̔͆̂̋̋͊̆͋̀̎͊͂̽̊̒̃͌͋̄̓̐͌͑̀̈́̋̽̏̃͌͘͘̕͝͝͝͠ͅç̵̡̹͍̫̩͇̤̠͚̻̳̼̻͆̔̀̒̔́̔̓̃͂̆̎̀̔̐̌́̌́̈̀͗̍͛̚̚͘͜͜ḩ̴̧̧̫̝̻̮͓̤̰̹͈͔̙͙͓͎͚̻̰̠͎͕͔̯̼̺̲͇̰̭̠͇̲̠̣͚̲̲͔̖̪͎̭͓̤̺̔̑̀̏̅̑̒͐͂̈̊̔͐̒̈́̒̾́̇̄͗̓͊͆̕̚ͅ ̸̢̧̨̧̪̳̲͔͚̦͖̟̳̲̗̠̦̬̫̪̖͚͚͔̘̗̤̹̦͉̘͖̫̲͔̤̟͓̯̤̣̖̑͋̌́̂͑̂́̒͠͝d̵̨̛̗̽̇͒̂̌̆̽̊͗̏̔̇͗̇̈́̿̑͌̋̍͌̓̆̍̊̓̉̇̈́̏͒̓̉̅́̒͗͊͊̉̈̄̌͑͆̽̌̀̕͘̕͠͝͝͠͠͠͠s̶̡̧̡̧̧̛̩͎͎͇̲̰̟̩̫̮̼̜̼̟̘̊͋͋͒̓̀͛̾͛́̒͒͂̈́͊̈̅͗̆͐̃͂̈́̍̾̂͑̑̌̃̀̈́̈̎͑͒̍̽̆̈́͐̃̊͒̚͝͝͝͝͝͝͠͠ͅc̷̡͖̺̦̺͈̹͇̯̟͔̞͙̫̤̜̹̫̬͙̝͍͚̮̼̝̱̱̱͈̦̽̑̍͑̑͜h̴̳̪̟͗̈́̀͐͂̎̒̃͛̊̔̒̀̂͌͋̽̀̌̈́̎̈́͋́͛̎̓̎͛͋͌̄̉̈́̽̈́̉̿̔̈́̊̚͘͝͝͠͝͝ͅ ̵̛̛̫͍͔͖̳̪̹͉͉̱̦͈̱͓̂̽̈́͌̄̓̍̋͒̾̇̏̂͑̔̑̉̕͝͝ͅď̷̛̪̫̘̰̳̿̔́̀̄͐̈́̽̌̏̃̑̑͂̄̈́̉̿͋́̚͠ş̵̨̨̢̨̧̢̲͉͖͓̟͕̜͕̠̼̲͎͓͎̹̮͓͕̩̅̄̔̆̊̀͂̇̐̊̔͋͆̐̃̄͒́͊͑̅̕̕͜͜͜c̶̡̡̨̛̛̰̥̟̤͉͖̼̤̤͈͎͚̝̝̜̼̖̙͕̪̳̈́̏̅̋̑̏̄͊́͒̏͂̈̈́̾̃̉̒̑͌̃̕̕͘̚͜͝͝͝ḩ̶̧͈̟̯̦̦͓̲͈̤̣̮̭̬̲̩͕̣̙̦̺̖̮͐̑͆́̄̅̂̎͆́͒̈́̐́͒́̾̅͑̈́̃̋̾̈́͌́͗́̽̍̎̽̆͑̈̌̄̐̆̃̈̒͐̎̑̕̚͘̚̚͜͠͝ ̸̨̧̨̨̡̧̧̧̛̮̝͕͚͓͎̼̲̻̞̪̺͔͍̬͔̜̼̙̘̹̣̲̲̙͓̺͓̩̲̪͍̹̳̙̝̟̰̠̯̩̦͈͕̣͚̗̙̰͈͉͇̳̙̲͌̈́̆͊͋́̾̇̅̄̍͋́͛́̚͜͜͜͜͠ͅͅͅ]̸̨̨̨̨̡͔͚͓̼̖̹͈̙͔̠͕̟̺̲̩̫͖̙̯͕̻͚͖͈̘̣̎̇̄̄̌̓͒̊͆͠
So, that leads us to point number one:
Now, I sometimes find myself working on a project
...with developers who seem to think of visual design
...as a purely cosmetic layer
...that sits on top of functionality.
A sort-of beauty tax
...that holds up the pace of implementation.
And don’t get me wrong.
I’ve met a lot of designers
...who seem to do visual design that way.
But they shouldn't,
...because when not focused on sales,
...which I'll talk about in a second,
...visual design should always be in service
...of making the app easier to use.
But before I demonstrate this,
...we should first look at MuseScore and ask:
In what way is it ugly?
Well,
...it’s a lot of little things that all add up.
The entirely gray background is an obvious first issue.
And the use of colour is...
...pretty ghastly.
I mean,
...look at this font selection.
I’ve never seen
...default red, black and turquoise
...combined like this before.
These pressed buttons are a little nasty too, and...
Urgh,
...those mixer controls look like a bad Flash game
...from the heyday of Newgrounds.com.
And then there’s the iconography,
...which is clumsy and inconsistent.
This is actually probably a good place
...to look at the functional importance of visual finesse.
So, iconography is a first cousin to
...typography,
...which is probably the most
specialised of the graphic disciplines.
And like a font,
...an icon set needs to be carefully considered
...so that it can be read easily.
For example,
...if you’ve ever looked at a typeface closely,
...you’ll notice a common baseline,
...like that seen here
...between the lowercase ‘u’
...and the lowercase ‘i’.
And then there’s a hundred other
little optimisations that you’ll find,
...like in Helvetica,
...where the lowercase ‘f’ and ‘t’
...line up like this.
These kinds of streamlined consistencies add up,
...and help the reader to process sentences
...without getting a headache.
Don’t believe me?
Then try reading a medium-length article
...in Papyrus,
...and let me know how you pleasant
you thought the experience was.
Seriously,
...why do people pick on Comic Sans so much
...when Papyrus is a thing that exists?
But anyway,
...icon sets work in a similar way.
You want to pay attention to the small details
...because it helps people navigate.
Visual awkwardness requires the brain
...to have to spend extra time
...interpreting what it’s looking at,
...and can make for a frustrating experience,
...especially when working for long periods of time,
...where you’re constantly scanning
...left and right...
Left and right…
Where is that?
Oh
There it is.
And to give a zoomed-in look at what I’m talking about,
...let’s look at these four in particular:
New,
Open,
Save,
...and Print.
I’m going to quickly break these down
...in a way that some might think is a little excessive.
But like I said earlier,
...these little things add up.
So, there are two garden-variety types of icon sets:
Ones that are outlined,
...and ones that are filled.
And since the brain reads these in different ways,
...it’s a good idea to choose either one or the other.
Here, there’s no consistency,
...with two being outlined
...and two being filled.
...and they look like they’ve come from different places.
This Save icon looks like
...it came from the site Font Awesome.
Let me just paste it in here to check.
Hmm.
Yeah, pretty similar.
The folder icon looks like
...it came from Font Awesome too,
...only from a completely different set.
Yeah.
Almost identical.
If I dig around enough,
...I’d probably be able to figure out
...where the other two are from,
...but it doesn’t matter.
The problem here is that the inspiration
...is coming from completely different places,
...and the result isn’t very structured or unified.
Let’s see how these same icons are handled
...by the open-source icon set
Clarity.
You can see here that they’ve
...matched up the baselines pretty nicely,
...although one is intersected half-way.
This detail on the Save icon
...is in line with the negative space on this Print icon.
This upper detail on Open
...lines up with this little detail on Print.
They also have this sharp-edged detail here,
...and then here facing in a different direction,
...which helps to give the set some character.
It’s pretty finessed.
And since it’s intended to be read at very small sizes,
...it doesn’t do a bad job.
A better and more legible set
...would be this one by Microsoft called:
'Segoe MDL2'
The baselines don’t intersect each other,
...these two details line up beautifully,
...and this detail in Save and Print line up too.
Pretty balanced and legible.
All together this would be much easier to read,
...and this is a set with hundreds of icons,
...all of them built in a way
...so that they can be easily read side-by-side,
...in no matter what ordering.
Now back to the MuseScore set.
The top as well as the baselines are intersecting.
You have negative space here,
...which is a different stroke height
that doesn’t line up properly,
...and this plus detail doesn’t match
...the height of the details in any of the other icons.
It’s not the worst thing ever.
It’s just clumsy, amateurish,
...and a little unpleasant to have to look at
...for hours at a time.
I wouldn’t go as far as to say that
...these icons will make people’s eyes hurt,
...because there’s not that many of them.
But over time,
...as the app becomes more complex and detailed,
...I'd hope that they begin to
introduce some more consistency.
Then there's colours.
Colours is generally a good way
of delineating between elements.
For example, in MuseScore,
...navy blue is used to mean something is selected.
However, it’s very similar to the colour
...used for these engraving markers.
It makes it a bit tough to tell
...if you’ve successfully selected something or not.
And it confused me a little bit,
...because there’s another similar turquoise colour
...being used in the sidebar.
Look!
You can see that some text is turquoise
...and some is black.
Maybe the turquoise colour represents
...values that are editable?
Uh, no,
...because if I edit something,
...the colour changes to black instead.
So,
...in this case when it’s this turquoise colour,
...it means it’s not been touched yet?
Have you confirmed that anyone understands this?
Do I even understand it?
I mean, look here,
...your tick-box colour looks like this,
...but if I tick it,
...that colour goes away.
And if I press this Reset thing,
...the colour comes back?
But hold on. I mean,
...if I click this note,
...all these values are black?
Er, I’ve never touched these before.
Wh- What's going on exactly!?
And when I press these notes,
...yes, they look selected,
...but that dark-grey/dark-blue combo
...is, well...
It's filthy.
I mean,\
...the icons look depressed.
I almost want to unclick them as an act of kindness.
And also,
...since you’re trying to delineate stuff,
...there’s a preponderance of icons and buttons here,
...which are slightly difficult to
distinguish from each other.
A bit of colour could potentially be useful here.
And-
Hold on.
Is that a tick-box with a reset button beside it?
So if I tick it,
...I can now have a second way to un-tick it?
Is this really necessary?
Now, as I mentioned earlier,
...the other requirement of visual design
...is that it can give an app an identity
...to help it stand out from the crowd,
...which in turn makes it easier to market.
One core part of this branding
...is logo design.
The MuseScore 2 logo was an eyesore,
...and it's been definitely improved with MuseScore 3,
...but it still looks a little...
...half-baked.
I mean,
...look at the Dorico branding for comparison.
It’s not amazing,
...but it’s nice.
You got this little D with the inverted note thing.
That’s neat.
With MuseScore,
...you have this fermata mark
...floating over the letter 'u'.
I mean...
It’s a bit lame, no?
It might just be me,
...I’m trying to figure out if there’s really
...something really clever being implied here,
...but, a fermata?
The marking that means you should
...pause for an unspecified amount of time?
Why that?
I’m just imagining the designer thinking,
"Hmm..."
"That 'u' looks a little bare."
"It needs something like..."
"No, we can’t use that."
"We need some sort of music-y type thing."
"So, um..."
"Yeah, that looks kinda..."
"Kinda cool."
"It’s open-source anyway,"
"...no one’s expecting anything nice."
Also, why is it an ‘mu'
...and not an 'ms'?
'muh'.
But even ignoring the symb-
[chuckles]
Ｍ Ｕ Ｈ
But even ignoring the symbolism-
Is- Is it-
It- It seems a bit wonky to me.
I don’t know if you can see it right away, but...
...everything’s leaning over to one side slightly.
It’s annoying.
Hold on, let me show you by grabbing the logo file.
Thanks, open source.
See the way the 'm' is angling
...slightly over to the right?
As if being blown by a breeze from the left?
No?
Okay, let me cut it out and invert it.
Now if I add a grid
...so you can see the half-way point.
Okay, it's pretty clear now.
The 'u' is swaying over to the left,
...and the 'm' to the right.
Why?
Well, I noticed on the MuseScore website
...that this logo was inspired by Helvetica Neue.
Really?
How?
I’ll investigate this.
Let’s just grab the lowercase 'm' from Helvetica Neue,
...and
Hmm.
Already looking pretty similar.
I’ve a feeling if I just isolate that curve
...on the underside of this lowercase 'm'
...and thicken it up a bit,
...and...
Yep.
I’m pretty sure I know how this logo was made.
Right, so in Helvetica,
...the lowercase 'm' leans over to the side
...to aid readability.
It works with the rest of the set.
This is a self-contained logo, so...
...leaning serves no purpose.
And it’s not like this combination looks great either.
So,
...this is what we get:
A bent-out-of-shape 'mu'
...with a random fermata mark on it.
It’s just janky.
This is the face of MuseScore.
MuseScore has a janky face!
So, what I would do?
Well,
...let’s work on the assumption that I can’t start again.
So,
...let me at least make a few tweaks.
And looking at it,
...I immediately notice a lot of half-circles.
Let's start with that.
I’ll create a circle
...based on the size of the current version.
I’ll move it over here and extend it.
Then double it.
Now I’ll do the same for the 'u',
And now we can turn the base of the 'u'
...into a fermata marking,
...so that they both have matching curves.
Fine.
Now if I pop that in a circle,
...let’s compare.
And you might want to pause here
...to fully appreciate the differences.
Here’s the original on the left.
Here’s my version in the middle,
...with a variation on the right.
Now, obviously, this is all subjective and you might think,
"Hmm."
"I prefer the one on the left."
And that's okay.
It's okay to be wrong.
Now with MuseScore,
...the lack of visual design finesse is evident,
...but that’s not the case with the design
...of its architecture and navigation.
In this area,
...I think it really shines.
In my Sibelius video,
...I spent quite a bit of time pointing out
...how completely unintuitive many
of the functionalities were,
...because they were hidden in places
you’d never expect to find them.
And the problem with this
...is that if you’re in the middle of writing some music,
...especially when you’re 'in the zone', so to speak,
...it’s immensely frustrating when
you have to halt what you're doing,
...in order to search around to find something
...you know you’ve used before.
Even worse if you need to down tools
...to go on a Google hunt.
Complex systems, when designed well,
...allow users to form strong mental models
...that help them to find things easily.
And, where possible,
...they should try to incorporate mental models
...that are widely used elsewhere.
A simple example of a common mental model
...would be the layout of a pop-up.
Here’s one.
So,
...tell me.
How do you close it?
See,
...we don’t need to think twice.
It’s a completely established mental model.
You go midway up the left-hand side,
...click on the double arrow,
...and slide down the ‘popup’ switch.
ᴅᴜʜ
And when you think about it like this:
"Where do I go to get something?"
...that’s when you can see the problems
If you want to add a marking
It’s hard to conceptualise.
...that you don’t use very often,
...where do you go?
It could be in here.
It could be in this big list.
It could be buried under one of the
...in the Text category under 'Styles'.
It could be in this widget.
It could be buried under one of the
...two different right-click menus.
Or it could have a unique place on the ribbon,
...like the guitar diagram seen here,
...or brackets in a different category here.
MuseScore beats this hands down.
The model is so simple I can describe it in a few words.
If you want to write notes,
...they’re up here.
If you want to add any other type of marking,
...they’ll be here in the left panel.
And if you want to move or alter
...something that’s already in your score,
...the options will be here in the right panel.
That’s it.
You now understand the layout of MuseScore.
So let’s say I’m looking for guitar diagrams.
Because I have a strong mental model of the layout,
...I know with a high degree of certainty where I’ll find it.
And when I drag it into the score,
...I have a pretty good idea
...that the options are going to appear here.
This is the kind of intuitiveness
...that all complicated apps should strive towards.
It’s actually quite reminiscent of the layout
...of a program called Sketch,
...which is also really easy to learn.
What’s more,
and this is something I really like,
...you can move these panels around
...in whatever order you want.
...there’s still quite a bit of clumsiness
And if you don’t like clutter,
...you can remove any options you don’t need.
But in saying that,
...there’s still quite a bit of clumsiness
...strewn around here and there
...that needs cleaning up.
Here’s a quick list I’ve put together.
Okay.
Are you ready for the pain?
Right. First off,
...you see all these things?
These blue UI elements,
...frames and hidden objects?
Sometimes I want to temporarily switch them off,
...so I can see how the score
is going to look when printed.
To do this,
...I need to untick these different options here.
But each time I untick one of them,
...the menu closes,
...so I have to navigate back up
...and open it back up
...in order to untick the next option,
...and it closes again.
Huueergh
Okay.
I’m done now.
I can see it.
I'm happy.
And now I want to turn them all back on,
...so I have to take four more trips
...back to the view menu again.
Will you...
Will you just leave it open?
Let me tick and untick what I want,
...and I’ll close it when I’m done.
Better yet,
...look how empty the right-hand
panel is when nothing is selected.
I mean, look at it now.
It’s the:
...panel.
I think we can get a bit more imaginative than that.
Perhaps when nothing is selected,
...it could show useful things,
...like, um
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
Well, that’s an idea.
In fact,
...there're tons of things you can potentially put in here
...that are currently buried in the top menu.
I also notice an option called:
‘Documents Side by Side’.
Oh, maybe this is what I need.
A kind of print preview?
Oh no.
No, it's just the same thing twice.
Okay. Well,
...I don’t want that.
I mean, no one in history has ever wanted that.
So let’s just close it.
Oh. It’s asking me to save another copy.
Nah, why would I want-
Oh,
...I’ve just deleted my entire project without saving.
Remind me why I have an option
...to see the same document twice?
Is it because you forgot to disable it
...when there’s only one document open?
I think it is...
Incidentally, if you have your part scores open,
...this is actually a pretty cool feature.
Now this next one is…
...insane.
So, a very common thing in score-writing
...is to want to change an instrument
...midway through the piece.
How do we do this?
My first expectation is to click on the bar in question,
...and then go to where I remember
the 'Instruments' option being.
No.
No instrument-change option up here.
That's okay though.
Let’s look around in the side panel.
Hmm. Not there either.
Okay, so now I’m going to look more
carefully through the left panel
...and, sure enough,
...good old left panel has what I need.
I love you, left panel.
And now, uh...
Oh
Okay, hold on.
It’s just text with no options.
Bad left panel!
[coughs blood in Russian]
Okay, I don’t know what to do now.
Time to consult Google!
Oh, a video!
Yeah.
Yeah. Uh...
Come on.
Y- Yeah.
Uh...
Who are you advertising to?
I have the app already!
"Hello,"
"...and welcome to another Quick Tips video."
[sighs]
"Sometimes you might decide to change an instrument"
Uh...
"...when you're writing a score."
Yeah.
"This bass guitar part, for instance..."
Okay, let’s just skip the video.
I’ll summarise.
So, I need to go to Staff Properties
...by right-clicking.
Yeah, well, I guess the app is full.
There’s nowhere else this option could possibly go.
So I go to Staff Properties
...and then hit another button.
Voilà!
Okay.
Now to change the instrument to a viola.
And, uh...
Oh, you’re kidding me.
It’s actually replaced the violin across the entire score?
So hold on.
How did-
How on Earth do I change to an instrument
...mid-way through the score?
Right.
Time for some precision-Googling.
I’m not holding out much hope for this.
Uh, okay. Ah!
Mid-staff changes,
...here we go.
Okay.
W- Wow, do I-
Do I really need all of this?
Erm, okay.
Scroll down, scroll down...
Ah, here we go!
Hold on.
Are you serious?
I have to right-click on that text
...to change the instrument?
I've to right click on this?
And it’s, like, the only unique option here too.
Yeah, because, um,
...there’s nowhere else this could possibly go.
So I change the instrument,
...and-
D- Did it do it?
Oh man, it didn’t even alter the text for me
...or change the clef,
...so I have to do all that manually.
W- What do you have against changing instruments?
So, yeah.
As I subtly alluded to a few seconds ago,
PUT IT THERE!
You let me change noteheads
and text values in this panel,
...and that’s great!
Do it for everything!
Now, we need to talk about part scores.
This took me ages to figure out.
You’ll find it under ‘File’,
...secreted away below the ‘Close’ option.
Not the most easy thing to find, but...
...that's not the worst sin ever.
Okay, let's open it.
What on Earth am I looking at?
Uh...
'Select Part'?
But there are no parts there, and...
Okay.
‘Edit Part’.
Uh...
Violin?
Hmm, alright.
Uh... Nothing's happening.
I think I’ll press 'enter'.
Oh.
That just closed it. Okay.
Okay, let's open it back up again.
So...
'Instruments in Score'.
That looks promising,
...but t- the '+' doesn’t do anything.
Uh, do I drag it here?
No.
Okay. So as a last resort,
...let’s press this button:
'New All’.
Oh...
Oh, that’s done something.
Okay, I think that did it!
Hurrah!
W- What do you mean ‘New All?’
What sort of copywriting is that?
It feels like the person responsible
...was in the middle of trying to get the phrasing right,
...and then just had a stroke!
Oh no…
No, no, no, no...
I don’t want to go back to that place.
No...
No, it's fading...
It's fading. W-
We’re okay, we're okay.
Save it for the Finale video...
I'm alright.
Okay.
Please don’t do that again to me, MuseScore.
So, let’s talk about something else.
In the world of design,
...we have a term called the:
...which refers to designs specifically aimed
...at helping new users understand how things work
...as quickly as possible.
You see this on mobile apps all the time:
...et cetera.
Impressively for the MuseScore team,
...they’ve just introduced their own version
...called ‘Tours’,
...little popups that appear at various points
...to explain where things are and how they work.
But again, I just get the sense that
...although they’ve built the right thing,
...they’re using it in slightly the wrong way.
So after launching the app,
...if you try to grab something from the left panel,
...a popup appears,
...that gives a general breakdown
of what the entire panel is for.
That’s nice,
...but it’s not what I’m planning to do right now.
Right now, I want to play around and find stuff,
...and these options don’t really
permit me to learn that way.
I can either give up what I was trying to do
...and press ‘Next’,
...which takes me through a
series of various descriptions,
...or I can close it.
Kind of holding me hostage here.
I like the idea of these descriptions,
...I just don’t want them right at this moment.
I find that this keeps happening as I'm working.
It's not that the instructions are bad,
...it's just that they tend to come when i don't want them.
When someone clicks on a thing,
...they probably have a very specific intent,
...and triggering a pop-up right at that moment
...is probably going to be an obstruction.
So, there are a few ways of improving this:
One is to provide a message
that works with the likely intent,
...and which doesn't prevent you from accomplishing it.
Oh, you're clicked on a marking?
You can drag it here and add it to your score.
Oh,
...you've selected an item in the score?
You can edit it over here.
Another way is to devise a method of
...letting the user decide when
explanations should happen.
Imagine, for example,
...that there was a button specifically for this.
Let's call it
...accompanied by, uh...
...I don't know, the MuseScore icon.
Hmm, maybe we can augment that a little.
It does looks a bit like an eye,
...so let’s make it an eye.
Ah.
It’s the all-seeing Eye of Terpsichore.
So, you click on something,
...the eye opens creepily to indicate that it’s active.
Then when you click on it,
...it tells you:
And that way, you get the information you want
...when you want it,
...not forced on you.
And as you move through the score,
...the eye could follow you around,
...wincing each time you specify
...Times New Roman as the font,
...rolling its eyes when you use
...more than three forte marks.
...and a unique function where,
...if you enter the name 'Einaudi' in the composer field,
...it gets glaucoma,
...shrivels up and never opens again.
I’m really liking this eye button.
I’m offering it up as a design that anyone can use.
You know,
...you could have it in other apps too,
...like, uh... Sibelius,
...where, if you click on it,
...it takes you to the Dorico download page.
Your time will come, Dorico.
Laugh while you can.
And that brings me to the final part of this video:
The importance of tiny details.
And from here on,
...I’m going to do something unusual:
I’m going to be praising Sibelius,
ᴡᴀɪᴛ, ᴡʜᴀᴛ?
...because despite its many problems,
...its notation functionality,
...the thing that made it famous,
...is still really good.
You’ll see what I mean in a moment.
But for context,
...it’s important to remind ourselves
...when making this comparison,
...that MuseScore has a very
different development setup.
The current team is tiny.
They don’t employ any professional designers right now,
...and they don’t have the capacity
...to perform controlled user-testing.
Instead,
...their feedback comes from a
community who makes feature requests,
...and they rely solely on open-source contributions
...and the design savvy of their
existing team to achieve them.
And although feedback and user requests
...are essential to knowing what to work on,
...solid designers are often needed
...to figure out how to provide them
...without massively over-complicating the app.
So, although the MuseScore team
...have done remarkably well up to this point,
...I think they could now do with
...some dedicated full-time designers
...to work through the sorts of
finesse I’m about to describe.
And you’d hope that under the
ownership of Ultimate Guitar,
...that’s now on the cards.
I guess we’ll have to wait and see.
Because, as it stands,
...there are hundreds of carefully
considered little efficiencies
...that Sibelius has,
...which MuseScore doesn’t,
...and these add up.
Let me show you what I’m talking about.
First off,
...let’s start with something tiny
...to show why it’s really useful.
Say I want to draw a slur over these notes here.
By default with both apps,
...I can press the shortcut ‘S’.
There we go.
Now, using another shortcut,
...I can quickly extend it like this.
Great.
Now, say I later come back
...and decide that I want to change the phrasing,
...so the slur mark covers only the first two notes.
Well, in MuseScore,
...there’s a shortcut to bring the slur backwards,
...but it’s actually faster
...to just delete it and start again.
Sibelius is even faster than this,
...because when I delete a slur,
...it automatically re-selects the note the slur began on,
...so I can add a new one immediately.
To see how much time this saves,
...I compared how long it took me
...to correct the phrasing
...of a two-bar piece of music in both apps.
In Musescore, after trying twice,
...I managed to do it in 1 minute and 29 seconds.
In Sibelius,
...I managed it in 1 minute and 8 seconds.
That's a difference of 21 seconds,
...which might seem trivial,
...but we’re only talking about 4 instruments and 2 bars.
If you make that 16 instruments,
...the difference is a minute and 20 seconds.
With 200 bars,
...now we're talking
...2 hours and 20 minutes of time
...purely spent moving your mouse to click on a note.
Sibelius does this for loads of things:
Performance directions,
...dynamics,
...lines, et cetera.
Musescore doesn’t do it at all.
And when writing music,
...you can really feel the difference.
Here’s another one:
In Sibelius,
...I can copy dynamics and hairpins at the same time,
...and then paste them immediately
onto another instrument,
...like this.
MuseScore doesn't do this.
I can copy and paste each dynamic marking,
...but I need to create the hairpin each time.
Also, in Sibelius,
...I can grab these three dynamics
...along with the edge of the hairpin,
...and drag them all to a new note.
In MuseScore, this is really painful.
Again,
...this has to be done one by one.
The time difference in this example is much worse,
...and this is partially to do with
the convention in MuseScore
...that you need to double-click on things
...in order to enter into an editing mode.
Seems like a good idea.
That might be neat,
...but it’s also slow.
How can I edit multiple hairpins
...if I have to double-click on one
to enter into a special mode?
What about copying and pasting?
Well, in Sibelius,
...if I copy these bars and paste them into the cello part,
...it also replaces the dynamics
...as well as the phrasing.
In MuseScore,
...if I do this,
...it keeps the original phrasing and dynamics too,
...which has now resulted in this mess.
Great.
Now I have to go and delete everything.
What about spacing?
Well, in Sibelius,
...I can click and drag on most elements to move them.
Here I’m just making a few improvements
...to make the score look nicer.
In MuseScore,
...in order to do similar improvements,
...I need to enter values in this sidebar.
That’s fine,
...although the objects aren’t tied together.
Look.
The barline is messed up now.
I have to select every bit of every bar first.
Again, really time-consuming.
I’m beginning to understand the use of this
...fermata mark now.
MuseScore.
Prepare to pause for an unspecified amount of time.
On the plus side,
...I can double-click on this note to do this.
That’s fun.
In Musescore,
...if I select a note,
...I can change the duration.
That’s good,
...but if I want to change the
duration of multiple notes at once,
...no such luck.
I can do that in Sibelius.
Another thing I can do
...is just hit one of these note values
...to immediately write in the score.
With MuseScore,
...I have to remember to turn on the note-input function.
Why?
What's the point of having a scenario
...where this button does nothing?
Then there’s playback.
One thing I make use of a lot
...is the ability to isolate instruments
...so I can hear exactly what they’re doing.
It’s one of the great benefits of music software.
But for some reason,
...I can’t do this quickly,
...say, by highlighting the instrument in question
...and pressing 'Play' like I can with Sibelius.
I have to instead bring up the mixer,
...turn on the solo button,
...listen to it,
...then come back to the mixer again
...and go back to normal.
It’s beyond irritating to have to
...keep navigating away from the score like this.
And now to my least favourite omission of all:
If I’m writing for piano,
...I rely on being able to press the left or right arrow keys
...to shift between chords,
...like this.
In MuseScore, however,
...you can’t hear the full chord,
...only the top note.
This means that,
...unless I have a piano to hand,
...and I often don’t because I write a lot while travelling,
...composing in MuseScore is
pretty much out of the question
...because the playback is just too slow,
...or at least it seemed that way,
...because there’s been an interesting development.
You see, I’ve been talking quite
a bit to the people at MuseScore
...while researching this video,
...mainly to help me get a sense of their history
...and current setup.
And along the way,
...I mentioned this last problem,
...and asked whether there was
a setting I could use to correct it.
And in response,
...a few days later I got an email letting me know
...that this had been added to their backlog.
Then a few days after that,
...it was implemented.
Here’s an example of a video
...taken by the developer who worked on it.
So you can expect to see this
improvement over the next few weeks,
...or it might even be out before this video is published.
I guess this is a good segue
...into my final thoughts about the app.
I don’t know if it comes across here,
...but I like MuseScore.
It’s far beyond what I was expecting,
...and it’s rate of improvement is pretty impressive.
On the visual side,
...I don’t really think this is a cause for much worry,
...since the fundamental navigation is excellent,
...and it seems to be headed in the right direction.
Although I think it could stand to look a bit nicer,
...this isn’t too hard to achieve.
Just a good reskin.
Pretty painless, compared to
...the overhaul I think Sibelius
needs for its entire navigation.
As for the rate of improvement,
...updates happen all the time
...and they’re effortless to install.
They also listen a lot.
So if you agreed with anything I’ve mentioned
...or if you've ideas of your own,
...make sure to say so in the comments.
They’ll be reading and taking notes.
Regarding notation and engraving,
...this is where MuseScore have
their work cut out for them.
Having worked on large-scale creation apps myself,
...I know how awkward it is
...to try and satisfy multiple different types of user
...with just one interface.
I’ve made a few suggestions for improvements here,
...but there’ll be thousands more from other musicians,
...and many of them will undoubtedly
contradict each other.
Charting a course through all of this
...that satisfies the most amount of people
...will be very difficult.
Sibelius seems like a good
choice if you’re a professional,
...but it’s a nightmare to learn
...and can often be maddening to use.
Getting really good at it takes months,
...but when you do get good,
...it’s pretty fast,
...and as I’ve shown,
...contains a lovely attention to detail.
MuseScore almost feels like
...it has the opposite problem.
It’s very easy to pick up,
...which makes it great for beginners
...or people who want to blast out
a score every once in a while,
...but it doesn’t yet have the
notation or engraving finesse
...that I think would suck in
professional users en masse.
But that could change quickly.
They have a strong and seemingly loyal user base,
...a great score-sharing community,
...the ability to push out updates quickly,
...the backing of a large company,
...and consistent leadership.
And, they’ve also got Terpsichore
...and Shostakovich on their side.
Any final thoughts, Shosty?
[chuckles softly]
𝓘 𝓵𝓲𝓴𝓮 𝓽𝓱𝓮 𝓶𝓾𝓼𝓲𝓬...
[chuckles get louder]
[chuckles intensify]
['chuckles intensify' intensifies]
[＇ｃｈｕｃｋｌｅｓ ｉｎｔｅｎｓｉｆｙ＇ ｉｎｔｅｎｓｉｆｉｅｓ]
[̵̹̲͕̞̬̫̪̯͔̬̰̞̬̽͛͜͠ͅ＇̶̢̡̬͎̦̱͓͈̫͕̪͎̠̲͕̪̣̖̪̰͈̰̠̮̟̈͌̒͑̋͋̎͆̃̽̌̎̂͑͠͠ｃ̷͇̹̻̣̯͇̗̘͚̰̪̯͓̦͂̑̽̐̑̓͗̔͛̕͠ｈ̸̢̢̢̥̠͕̳̘̠̺̺͍̻̜̪̜̞̟̫̘̙̳͇̼̇̍̊̀̈̈͌͋̐͑̓͋ｕ̴̢̧̢̡̢̘̦̯̝͓͙̭̙͕̼̬͕͉͔͇̭̳̜̾͋̍̓͐̄͗̽̑̊́̋͛̓̄̆͘͠ｃ̵̧̩̖̼͆̽̈́̇̓̍̒̿̓͂̔͆ｋ̶̢̧̟̦̙͇̲̙̜͇̪̺̰̞͊ｌ̵̼̭̻̬̼̪̭̼̞̩̫̞͉̓̀ｅ̷̨̯͔̳̜̱̠̟͖̭̱̜͓́̾̇̈́̈́̈́̇͆̍̒̈́͐̔͗̋͐͘ｓ̵̨̛̮͙̙̝͕̰̘͙̭͕̮̼̟̼̬̱̪̹̞͇̐͌̑̐̑͛̓̈̌̾͂͊̾̈́͌̂̏͒̊̇̚̕͜͝ ̵̨̱̝̮̰̤͓̲̞̫̜͔̟͍̭̺̣̺̯͒͂̾́̃͛̃ｉ̶̧̡̜̣͖̼̼̼̼͚͓͍̠̳̯̖͍͕͖͖̯̹̀̑̈́́̍̊͒ͅͅｎ̴̡̮͈͖͔̭̰͇̦̝͇͓͈͕̯̥͕́̅̍̒̃͝ｔ̶̢̙̪͖̭̬̤͔̬̤̘͚͚͎͖̈̉͋̋̏̀̇̆̽̆̈́̓̆͘͜͝ͅｅ̷̡͙͖̱̘̺͎͔͍̣̬̼͍͙͓̣̝̞͙̥̱͖̮̊͛̉͂̀̾̌̽̏̇̈́͛̐̓̋́͊̊͘͘͠ｎ̵̰̯̯͇͗͑̔̏̔̅̒̏̈́̀͌̿́̏͗̿̄̾͘̕͝ｓ̵̺̭̲̳̣͈̹̅̓̿̋̔̋͋͌̆̈́͐͋̆̒͒̈͌͝͝ｉ̶̡̢̨̺̦̪̮̹̮̻̹͉͙̰͈̝̲̺͙̗̹͎͇̓̈́̏͂͗̋̿̾̊̄̊͗͜͝͝ͅｆ̵̡̨̰̪̻̺̪̝̖̲͖͍̘͕͒̀̒͐̓͗͑̕͜ｙ̵̨̢̛̯̭̰̦͇̱̙̝̳̭̹̰̣̫͕̥̠̻̦̭͍̳̐̀̑͂͊̏͒̿͌̑̀̊̌̈̆͛͗͜＇̷̧̛͕͓̼͕̄͋͐͒ ̵͉̺̥́̈́̇͗̏̐̆͂̓̿̃̈͠ｉ̶̢̢͔͈̯̯̪̟̥̱̪̇͒̈́̇͒̈́͊́̉̑̓͗́̋ｎ̵̧̢̨̰̱͉͍̻̖̲͓̜͓̜͔̞̞̯͓̼̥̟̟͕͐͝ｔ̵̢̡͉͇̖̖̘̬̺̠͎̼̹̯̜̠̻̳̫͖̙͌̆̓̅̒͆̀ｅ̴̨̱̺̍̽̊͒̊̋̌͌̾͋̚͘̚ｎ̶̡̥͙͔͍̅͒̾͗ｓ̴̘̥̜͍̰̪̞̟͇̰̬̉̿͌͘ｉ̵̧̻̫̭̙̤̺̞̝̩͕̻̺̝̫́̇̃̓̈́̐̄͒̓̊͂́̈͐͒̇̂̏̓̇̿̕͜ｆ̷̻̞̮̩̱͙̼̳̭̱͉̯̈̏̄̈́̎͒̈́̏̇̒͒̈́̌̍̎̔͂̐̍̌̈́̚͝͝͠ｉ̶̧̬͎̬̖̜̭͈̳̎̒̄̿̌̈́̆̄͂͌͂͑̾̾͂̈́͂́͗̉̕̚̕͝͝ͅｅ̶̛͍͕͎̳̜̘̺͇͇̜̂͌̐̒͐͂̽̄̀̔̎̈́̋͜ｓ̸̨̢̢̛͚͇̹͚̣̬̙͍͉̗̲̩̘̱̮̞̤̅̈͊̄̿̔͆͗̅̆͛̈̇̈́̐̿̈͐̓̆͘͘͜͠ͅ]̵̢̢̨̧̨̛͕̜͓͇̙̳͙͙̓̓̓͂̈́́̓̈́̉͋̎͂̈́̈́̈́̉̈́͌͘͜͜͝
[̷̨̧̧̢̟̲̺̘͍̻͕̺̣̭͈͇̹̹̯̳̟͓̜̪͈̬̝̬̥̄͗̐̈́̆̾͂̽͑̈́͜͜͠＇̵̡̡̮͉̻̼̞̳̥̬͙͔͔̯̤͎̻̺̖̳̤̳̭̩͕̯̰̤͈͕͇̫̞̬̰͖̫͉̜̥̳̊̈́͗̑̍̋͆͂͐̂͜͜͠ͅｃ̷̢̡̖͕̩̝̝͔̰̜̩͖̦͚͉̪͖͍̜̖͍̘̼͔̞̹́͜ｈ̵̮̞̖̝̱̰̝̜̬͎̮̥̟͉̮͈̔̑̃̒̀̇́͗͋͗͑͛͘͠ͅｕ̷̧̡̡̳̲̠̖̰̰̣̟̱̫̯̩̭̤͖͌͋̀̆̇͛͑̃͐͋̍͋̐̑̃̑̃̀͐̇͑̈́͂̋͑ｃ̴̢̗̰̰̔̑̈́͊̎̏̊͝ｋ̷̢̡̡̡̛̛̛̺̦̜̳̪͔͌̆̂͑̈́͌͐̄̈̆̐͌̀̊͛̽͋͗͑͗͑͊̎͊̆̈́̒̓͗͋̄͒͒͘͠͝ͅｌ̷̨̳̼̰̪͉̜̝̤̲̺͕̀̎̈́̐̌͗͊̓̎̽̈́̒̐̋͛̒͊̄̏̓̇̇͂̂͒̀̈̓̎͘̚̕͠͝͠ｅ̸̨̡̜͇͎͇̦̻̤̼͈̣̜̱̻̦͔̊̍̃̒̑ͅｓ̷̨̧̧̨͓͖͕̪̦͍̝̞̥̹͉̼̪̞͔̩̩̠͍̗͚̹̻̓́̊̒͆͛͑̈́̉́͐̌͑͠ ̴̡̳̟̖͍̫̲̥̝̲̯͎͓̹̬̦͕͉̲͔̞̳̘̙͔͚̪̖͚̩̣̠̜̑͊̈́͐́̏̈́̉͊́̀̾̀͊̈́̋̓̀͜ｉ̴̡̡̡̧̡̨̛̩̖̬̦̼̭̜̰̱͔̳̗̝̤̺̤͎̤̉̀͆̚ͅｎ̶̧̨̧̛̛̫̼̘͇̰̥̬̦̝͍̙̻̺̄̅̋͒͌̔̋̆́́̕͘̚͝ｔ̷̨̡̧̨̨̖͇͈̘̪͉͎̜̭̪͚̯̰͓̳̼̲̼̭̼̩̮̲̣̖̠͂̄̋̑̀͐͆̐̉̿̔̽́͋̉͗͌̏̍̇̒͗̽̆̓̒̕̚̕͝͝͝͝ｅ̷̢̱̰̯͕͙͔̤̤̰̤̬͈̯͎̟̼͕̪͇̼͙̻͓̯̠͕̱̄̅́̿̓̈́̐̾̐̀̈́́̈́̕ｎ̴̢̨̡̱͕̯̼̲̼͉̺̳̦̙̱̊̄̀̈̐̓̇̌̿̿̄̚͜͠͝ｓ̵̧̤̤̙̻͇͈̭̱̙̞̙̗͍̟̹̇͂͌͋͋͑̒̌͊̌͌̏̿͊͒͛̆͛̊̾̈́̋̾̅͂̿͜͜͜͝͝͝͝ｉ̵̪͚̂̐̔͘̕ｆ̵̢̡̡̳̖̣̘̬̲͍̱̙͇̰̙̥͚̺͕̙̟̪͈̬̬̰͉̲͎͖̹͉̮̯̣̤̜̠̜̫͕̯̃̾͂̃̈́̀͌͂͆̿̾͋̇̿̂͛̑́̿̏̂̀͋̾̌̈́̅̇͐̐͗̾̕̕͘͘͜͝ͅｙ̴̛̻̗̩̺̦́͋̏͋́̽͂̓̅͆͑͌͑̔̒̚͜͜͝＇̸͇̏̌͊̌͊͐̊́ ̸̡̢̜̠̙̠̠̼̬͇̮͈͖̬̯̮̬̦̱̩͂̆̊̏̓̅̇̿́͂͂̋́́ｉ̴̨̨̢̢̰̖̪̞̝̜̝̹̩͎̮̝͕̱̖̟̝̠̻̘̣̬͎̜̹̞̗͕̫̞̩̦̮͉̞̝̹͓̘̒̽̏͒̈́̾̀͛̆̎̀̍̆̂̓̒̒͜ｎ̶̭̦̼̓̈́́̾̋̅͆̓̔̀̈́̒͒̀͆̈͛̿̌̅͂͂̀͆̇͊͛́͂͊̕͠͝ｔ̶̡̮̲̪̦̱̄̅̏̍͂̓͐̿̊́̈͐͋͑̇̍́̅͊̈̀̀̎̓̆̈́̈͘͠ｅ̷̨̨̧̨̛̹̯̣͙͍̼̣̼̜̖̦̽͆̈́͗̊͗͋̏̓̈́̓̂̒̆̎̔̏̔́͌̉͛̈́̈́͂̋̍͋̏̊͌̀̏̚͘̚̚͜͠͝ｎ̵̨̢̧̢̩̭̹̳̖̞̮̤̱̤̘͚͕͇̗̙̟̟̤͈̫̺̮͍̫̣̗͔̯̩͊͑̒͌̃̉̑̀́͛́̋̑̊̒͐̾͒́̓̓̆̅̓̚̕͘͜͜͜͜͝ｓ̵̡̢̧̝͙̜̼͖̠̮̫̯͙̠̟͇̟̼͇̖̮̺͔̤͎͎̻̱̖̟̹͇̩̟̝̼̝̙͎̦͕̠̈̔̌̓̑̂̍̈́́͌͐̈́̎͑̎̌͐̎͐̀͊͂̏͒̿̏̈́́̚͜͠͠͝ｉ̵̛̳͖̝̱̮̱̟̺͉̯̦̳͐̈́̍͑̀ｆ̴̨̥̺̻̠͌̈́͛̄̈́̓͑̓͆̍́̾͘͘͘͠͠͠ｉ̸̡̨̲͎̪̖͉̫̻͚̯͖͎̭̗̣̞͕̖̩̟͖̣̖̜̂̑́̾̑̂̽͐̈́͗̈͜͠͠ͅｅ̶̡̢̧̡͚̗̪̼̖̦͕͕͙̦̬͉͍̥̭͐̽͛̍́ͅｓ̴̢̨̲̭̝̗͇̮̙̝̤̜̬͙͖̙͙̤̟̲͙̲̬̜͓̠̰̪̜̲͊͒͛̂͋̀͗̆̎̀̏͛̍̀̚̚͜͝]̷̧͓̯͎̠̙̯̥̩̻͈̜̥̭͕̻̑̄́́̌̈́͂̄͌̈͗́͂̐́͑̕̕
D̷̢͇̬̦̫̝͚͌̈͘Ş̶̧̧̭̭̗̙̫̦̼͋C̴̨̲͕̯̤͔̞͕̐̔͑̃Ḩ̶́̑͌̆̂̓̂̒́ ̸̡̪̠̹̲̻̀̽̔̑̎̇́̓̏̈́ͅḐ̶͇͐͋͐S̸̝̜̮̝͌̉̒̆͝ͅC̸͎̲̲̃͂̊̌̊̇͐̏͝H̷̨̜̰͉̹̪̹̐́̍̚ ̴̧͇͔̪̏̅́͐̓D̸̡̨̗̺̥͈͇͔͆̅̈́̿̆̕ͅD̵̨̡̙̗͎͉̈͜S̵̰͖̪̹͓̪͇̣̀͗͑̂̐̄͊͝͠ ̴̨͈̼̤͚̤̗̖̔̀̏Ĉ̴͔̱̦͕͓̜̫̝̭͂͒͐̐̾̓̆H̷̼̣͓̖̅͂͝D̷̙̬̺͖͉̤̗̝͆͆̆̾̉̕̚S̵͍͈̣̻̝̜̭̭̪̫͆́̅͂͂C̴̲̰̰̦̫͉̲̃̊̈́H̷̨̼̭̙͇͓͈͊̿D̸̡̖̪̱̣̙̉̽̔̄̽̀̈̀̈́Š̵͇̀̌͐C̷̻̗̭̣̮̓̈́͌̽͐́̕͝͝ ̶̧͙͉̯̆̐Ȟ̸̪̂̎̄̀͐̃̀͆̚s̴̨̮̙͚̝͓͈͐̎́F̵̨̩̺͓̟͕͓̥͍̭̓h̴̳̍̀̂̿̏͘̚͝ ̵̺͆̍͊́̐̿̃͒̀͝ ̸̧̪̯̗̮̹̖̋ͅd̴̢̢̰̂͊͆̎̍̾̈̅͠c̵̢̝̙̳̟̖̝̼̫̃̄̕s̴̛͈̝͉̮̲͇̟̎́̅̿̓̋h̴̳̹̮̭͖́̓͆̌̓̉̚F̷̧̪̣͔͙̩̬͕̥́̽̒̿̌͜͝F̵̜̀̈́D̶̜̳̲͍̂̃̀̾̎͝ ̸̡̼̫̬̱̞̤͕͚̑̎͜͠d̶̛̺͂̅̄̋̄̊͌͋̒ḉ̴͒̈̈́̚͝h̵̨̧̼͖͔͖̗̣̿ ̶̢̙̐́̋̀̃͌̾̅s̵̡͇̻͆͐́c̶̢̛͇̲̗͍͍͇̠̦̽́́͒́͗͑ḑ̴̛̱̹͎͎̲̞̪̩̓̓̂̓͒̂̂̍c̵̨̃̀͛̈́̐̽́ḍ̷̳̟̂͆͆̎́͘̚̚͝͝/̸̧̺͔̟̩̪̉̾́̇̓̇̆̈́͘-̴̧̧̛̜̦̮̀͌̅̂̌͌̇͜͝4̵̘̖̮̖̀̈̔̈́́͐̈́⍰̴̝̥͍̱͈̈̿̊̾̂͘͝s̷̢͖̼̰̳̱̪͔̅̀̽̀̉̆͜h̵̞̳͔̮̖̲̑̇̅̇̓͑̈́͛͝d̶̺̟̘̞̻̼̣͚͂̇c̸̨̮̖̗̹̿͒͐͗̍\̵̧̙̰̑͆͒̅̆͗̔̑͒ ̶̼͉̙̝̮̲̒̿͒͝⍰̴̨̢̡̭̹̼̫͕̄̓͊̏͌́́̊ͅ[̶̛̞͙̜͕̳͇͈͒̀̚ ̵͉̖̠̓͗̄̓̔h̵̢̘͓͚́̈̐̓̀͒̕͠s̸̡̨͙͎͊̓ ̶̡͓͉͎͓͓͒͒͋͛̿̆͊͠͝c̸̢̭̳̒̾̉̚͝ḣ̵̦̻͉͓̣͓͂̃̒̔̾d̴̡͕̙̙̹̟͓̙̼̀̉̃̓⍰̵̳̬͔̄͆̈̈́̃͑⍰̵̡͈̘̫̙͇̟̈́͐͛͆͒̓͛̂͘͜͜͠ͅ⍰̶̢̢̨̭̟̻̥̩͇̄̍̑͌̒̉̕⍰̷̢̨͈͙͇̮̖̞̐̌̈̐͑̒́͛͜ͅ⍰̴̹̟͔͙̀̈́̍⍰̴̙̰͎͙̫͓͍̍͗̃͛́͘⍰̷̬̯̬̲̖̬̻͐̓̈́̿̾̂̐̚c̵̢͔̙̪̹̤̆̔̆ ̴̺̜͓̥́͌̃̽̓̃h̷̖̳̝̑̏͐̈́͑ ̸̯͓̭͚̣̟̟͍̝̐͋d̶͔̫̼̼͉͚̰̾̎ ̷̖͉̝̼͇̭̭̍́̈̓̀̎̀̈́̄c̵̬̥̺͚̋̏s̵͍̘͎͎͔̝̞̹̎̂̔̀́͝ͅh̶̨̧̬̠̦͓̦̝̚d̷͕̓̿̈́́̆̌̕s̷̹̲̠̮̓̃̌̒́͝⍰̴̼̟̽͊̅͐̿͊ẅ̵̹̃͌͆́̄̽͐͘f̴̡̣͓̳̩͚͖̘̓̇̔̂̉̍̇̚͝͝ͅȃ̴̲̜̪̄̎͊͐͒q̴͎͌̊̆̆̑̀̈̕5̴̥̔̏̍̔̿͘m̴͇̖͒́̃t̸̗͎̩̖̭̙̣̹̦̏̏̓̿́͘8̶̳́̈̋̒ ̵̢̀͋̊̔̌̂̚̚ͅͅͅp̸̛͕̩̦͕͖̍̈́̑͐̾̾̽̚͝9̸̮͓̻̱̲̭̮̰͓̱̌̿͒͋̓p̸̢̟̝͓̭̳̫͚̲̆́͊/̸͉̭̻̲̹̙̼̮̀͋̄͒̈́͝ų̴̨͙̖̤͍̹̮̗͈̎̑̒̍͐͘5̷̡͉̻̭̼̦̤͖́̈͊̿́͂̿͆͝ͅ ̷̥̩͍͎͉̥̜͇͍̬̐̊̈͋̚͘͠⍰̶̡̢̫̟̞̦͓͔̖̘͆̅k̵̢͍͖̬̬͎͐͗̿̄̄̒̒ͅ8̸̢̛̤͕͍̳̙͈̬̌̽͊̈̓͆͘E̴̢̹͎̳̺͈̬̺̿̓̏͘̚R̸͙̹̠̤̪̹͖̙̠̅͌̉̂̀̃̃̓̆R̷̢̰͙̝͚̝̬̼͚̼̒̊̿̇̽̈́͑̉Ọ̵̰̖̰̙̩̽̎̃̃̈̆͛R̶̹̙̩͚͛́̃̄͐͂ ̷͉̜̬͖̼͍̯͓͓̹̈́̌̐̕i̷̮̣̟͍̜̻̫͈̇͘͜ͅw̶̫̻̫̤̆͂́͐̆͛͊̚͝[̴̨̡͕̘̻̖̦̳̀́̑͒̒͆̈́̈́6̶̲͔͇͉͕͚͉͔̿̿͌͒̎̑̋͘͝ì̷̯̖̬͔̺̆̽̽͛̅͛͜͝,̸̹͇̼͠ỳ̷̦̲̺̞̮̂̀̍̌̈͆̓̍n̵̻̜̿̉̌̎͂̕⍰̶̢͙͕̼̘͔̥͒͛̌́̕̕͠[̵̥̼͕̓ ̸̧̪͚̙̮̼͈̹̰̹̾̿̔̈́̍0̵͎̠͋͑͛̑͜,̴̖̳̟̮̳̓͆̑̒͗͝ȩ̷̝̩̘̻̻̩̙̅͋͘ͅ9̴͔̲͔̥̫̪͊̾͑̓͆͜͠ŗ̶̧̝͔͖̺̻͎̐́̂̇͗͋͂͘͝/̶̛̗͎̤͙̖̖̹̀́̐̃̔̚͝ư̸̛̹̈́̋̊͗t̸̡̞̬̄̄͑̃͆͠ ̵̞͉̑͂͛́͠ ̶̹̹̦̘̼̰̠̎̕ ̶̡̘͑̄́́́̿̏̚̕ͅv̸̯̂͒̒̓͂͑̓̄͂'̶̯̹͇̙̤̃̎̔̋̎/̸̯̫̪͔̖̗̽͛̍́
̶̳͈̪̭̳͚͔̩͂̉̈́L̴̯͋̃̈́͝͝I̸̫̹̞̊̿͐͘Y̴͚͓͕̪̎̓̄̈̐̈́ç̸̢̲̦̞̃̐́͑̄̓̃̍ĭ̷̡̝̺͓͙̆̌̈͒͆͠ủ̷̙̯̩͂̔̌̃̅̉͠͠y̸̢͙̫̏̄̆̂͛̓̅͗͛̀C̸̛͉͍͍̫̲̈́̓̇̍̌͝Ò̶̡͍̩̰̖̞͍̥̋̀̎͜Ŭ̶̡̦̣̜̻̻͔́̈̊̄́̎͘͠͝ ̴̩͎͊͒t̸̢̠͕͕̖̪͛̊̔̆̌̎͂̿͝͝ơ̴̯̟̼̲͔̌̄̈̍̕ͅB̶̠̟̰̰̖̥͎́̀͘̚͜Į̷̞̺̳̘̝̅̿̊̕Y̴̛͎̰̜̥̹̓̈́̒͊̑T̵̪̣̭͈̩̗̱̔́̿ͅͅO̴͚̩̳̝͍̦̯͓̔̒B̴̛̯̔͋͜-̸̨̞̝͕̘͖̘̱͌̓̒̆̉̀͑̿̚͝0̶̛̱̖̫̿̿̏̓̓́͆̍̚8̵̰͇̯͔̫̯͎͙̣̿̏̂͋̀͘̚ͅȩ̸̩̦͔̻̼̱̟̳̓͌͂̉͌͐͂r̴̛͙̰̹͉̠͖̥͋͑͌͑̈́͑͗R̶̛͎̳̪̟̦Ő̷̞̯̹̻̤̇͝R̶͉̞̗̫̩̮͔̱̜̭͂̂͛̇̓͂[̶̨͈̳͉̪͚͖̳̬͇̄͝
[Inception bwam]